<sequence><author><surname>Amaste</surname>, <given-names>Jon</given-names></author> & <title>Elías-Olivares, Lucía (Hrg.): Spanish in the United States. Sociolinguistic Aspects</title>. <other>Cambridge</other> <year>1982</year>.<raw>Amaste, Jon & Elías-Olivares, Lucía (Hrg.): Spanish in the United States. Sociolinguistic Aspects. Cambridge 1982.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Barker</surname>, <given-names>G.C</given-names></author>.: <title>Social functions of language in a Mexican-American community</title>. <source>Acta Americana</source> <volume>5</volume>. <year>1947</year>.<raw>Barker, G.C.: Social functions of language in a Mexican-American community. Acta Americana 5. 1947.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bechert</surname>, <given-names>Johannes</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Wildgen</surname>, <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names></author>: <title>Einführung in die Sprachkontaktforschung</title>. <other>Darmstadt</other> <year>1991</year>.<raw>Bechert, Johannes & Wildgen, Wolfgang: Einführung in die Sprachkontaktforschung. Darmstadt 1991.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fishman</surname>, <given-names>Joshua A</given-names></author> et al. <title>Bilingualism in the barrio</title>. <other>Bloomington</other> <year>1971</year>.<raw>Fishman, Joshua A. et al.: Bilingualism in the barrio. Bloomington 1971.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fishman</surname>, <given-names>Joshua A</given-names></author> (Hrg.): <title>Lanugage Loyalty in the United States; the Maintenance and Perpetuation of Non-English Mother Tongue by American Ethnic and Religious Groups</title>. <other>Niederlande</other> <year>1966</year>.<raw>Fishman, Joshua A. (Hrg.): Lanugage Loyalty in the United States; the Maintenance and Perpetuation of Non-English Mother Tongue by American Ethnic and Religious Groups. Niederlande 1966.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fitzpatrick</surname>, <given-names>Joseph P.</given-names></author> <title>Puerto Rican Americans. The Meaning of Migration to the Mainland</title>. <other>New Jersey</other> <year>1971</year>.<raw>Fitzpatrick, Joseph P.: Puerto Rican Americans. The Meaning of Migration to the Mainland. New Jersey 1971.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>García</surname>, <given-names>John</given-names></author>: <title>Language Use, Occupational Status and Wage Earnings - Chicanos in Southwestern Labor Markets</title>. <other>Arizona</other> <year>1978</year>.<raw>García, John: Language Use, Occupational Status and Wage Earnings - Chicanos in Southwestern Labor Markets. Arizona 1978.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Grebler</surname>, <given-names>Leo</given-names></author>, <author><surname>Moore</surname>, <given-names>Joan W.</given-names></author> <author><surname>Guzman</surname>, Ralph <given-names>C</given-names></author>.: <title>The Mexican-American People, the nation’s second largest minority</title>. <other>New York</other> <year>1970</year>.<raw>Grebler, Leo, Moore, Joan W., Guzman, Ralph C.: The Mexican-American People, the nation’s second largest minority. New York 1970.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Ornstein-Galicia</surname>, <given-names>Jacob</given-names></author> (<title>Hrg.): Form and Function in Chicano English</title>. Florida <year>1988</year>. <editor>Statistisches Bundesamt</editor> (Hrg): <source>Länderbericht USA</source> <other>Wiesbaden</other> <year>1994</year>.<raw>Ornstein-Galicia, Jacob (Hrg.): Form and Function in Chicano English. Florida 1988. Statistisches Bundesamt (Hrg): Länderbericht USA. Wiesbaden 1994.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Turner</surname>, <given-names>Paul</given-names></author> <title>R.(Hrg.): Bilingualism in the Southwest. Tucson 1973. Commission on Civil Rights (Hrg.): Puerto Ricans in the Continental United States: An Uncertain Future</title>. <other>Washington 1976</other><raw>Turner, Paul R.(Hrg.): Bilingualism in the Southwest. Tucson 1973. Commission on Civil Rights (Hrg.): Puerto Ricans in the Continental United States: An Uncertain Future. Washington 1976.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Steiner</surname>, <given-names>Stan: La</given-names></author> <author><surname>Raza</surname></author>. <title>The Mexican Americans</title>. <other>New York</other> <year>1969</year>. <other>Weinrich, Uriel</other> <source>Languages in Contact. Den Haag 1953/76</source><raw>Steiner, Stan: La Raza. The Mexican Americans. New York 1969. Weinrich, Uriel: Languages in Contact. Den Haag 1953/76.</raw></sequence>