<sequence><author><surname>Peter</surname> <given-names>Beidler</given-names></author>, <title>The Turn of the Screw. Introduction: Bibliographical and Historical Contexts</title>. <other>Boston</other>, <publisher>Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press</publisher> <year>1995</year><raw>Peter Beidler, The Turn of the Screw. Introduction: Bibliographical and Historical Contexts. Boston, Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press, 1995</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Marxist</surname></author> <title>Criticism and The Turn of the Screw in The Turn of the Screw</title>. Boston, <year>1995</year><raw>Marxist Criticism and The Turn of the Screw in The Turn of the Screw. Boston, 1995</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Wayne Booth</surname></author> "<title>He began to read to our hushed little circle: Are we Blessed or Cursed with Our Life with The Turn of the Screw ? in The turn of the Screw, herausgegeben</title> von <editor>Peter G. Beidler</editor> <other>Boston</other>: <publisher>Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press</publisher> <year>1995</year><raw>Wayne Booth, "He began to read to our hushed little circle: Are we Blessed or Cursed with Our Life with The Turn of the Screw ? in The turn of the Screw, herausgegeben von Peter G. Beidler. Boston: Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press, 1995</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Henry</surname> <given-names>James</given-names></author>, <title>The Turn of the Screw in The turn of the Screw and other short novels</title>, <other>New York</other> <publisher>Signet Classic of Penguin Books</publisher> <year>1980</year><raw>Henry James, The Turn of the Screw in The turn of the Screw and other short novels, New York: Signet Classic of Penguin Books, 1980</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stanley Renner</surname></author> <title>Red hair, very red, close-curling: Sexual Hysteria, Pysiognomical Bogeymen, and the "Ghosts" in `The Turn of the Screw' in The turn of the Screw, herausgegeben</title> von <editor>Peter G. Beidler</editor> <other>Boston</other>: <publisher>Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press</publisher> <year>1995</year><raw>Stanley Renner, Red hair, very red, close-curling: Sexual Hysteria, Pysiognomical Bogeymen, and the "Ghosts" in `The Turn of the Screw' in The turn of the Screw, herausgegeben von Peter G. Beidler. Boston: Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press, 1995</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bruce</surname> <given-names>Robbins</given-names></author>, "<title>They don't much count, do they?": The Unfinished History of ,The Turn of the Screw' in The turn of the Screw, herausgegeben</title> von <editor>Peter G. Beidler</editor> <other>Boston</other>: <publisher>Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press</publisher> <year>1995</year><raw>Bruce Robbins, "They don't much count, do they?": The Unfinished History of ,The Turn of the Screw' in The turn of the Screw, herausgegeben von Peter G. Beidler. Boston: Bedford Books of St. Martin's Press, 1995</raw></sequence>