<sequence><editor>American Council</editor> <title>on the Teaching of Foreign Languages: Standards for Foreign Language Learning. Preparing for the 21 st Century</title>. [Online] <url>http://www.actfl.org/public/articles/execsumm.pdf</url> (<other>1.3.2001</other>).<raw>American Council on the Teaching of Foreign Languages: Standards for Foreign Language Learning. Preparing for the 21 st Century. [Online] http://www.actfl.org/public/articles/execsumm.pdf (1.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Apelt</surname>, <given-names>Werner</given-names></author>: „<title>Nachdenken über Fremdsprachenunterricht und -didaktik in Deutschland zur Jahrhundertwende</title>“, in: <source>Fremdsprachenunterricht 1/2000</source> S. <fpage>2</fpage> - <lpage>4</lpage>.<raw>Apelt, Werner: „Nachdenken über Fremdsprachenunterricht und -didaktik in Deutschland zur Jahrhundertwende“, in: Fremdsprachenunterricht 1/2000, S. 2-4.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bach</surname>, <given-names>Gerhard</given-names></author>: „<title>Interkulturelles Lernen</title>.“ In: <editor>Johannes-P. Timm</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Englisch lernen</source> <title>und lehren. Didaktik des Englischunterrichts</title>. <other>Berlin</other>: <publisher>Cornelsen</publisher>, <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>192</fpage> - <lpage>200</lpage>.<raw>Bach, Gerhard: „Interkulturelles Lernen.“ In: Johannes-P. Timm (Hrsg.): Englisch lernen und lehren. Didaktik des Englischunterrichts. Berlin: Cornelsen, 1998, S. 192-200.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Banks</surname>, <given-names>James A</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Banks, Cherry</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></author>.: <title>Handbook of research on multicultural education</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>Macmillan</publisher>, <year>1995</year>.<raw>Banks, James A. & Banks, Cherry A.: Handbook of research on multicultural education. New York: Macmillan, 1995.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Banks</surname>, <given-names>James A.</given-names></author> et al. <title>Diversity within Unity. Essential Principles for Teaching and Learning in a Multicultural Society</title>. <other>Seattle</other>: <publisher>Center for Multicultural Education</publisher> <year>2001</year>.<raw>Banks, James A., et al.: Diversity within Unity. Essential Principles for Teaching and Learning in a Multicultural Society. Seattle: Center for Multicultural Education, 2001.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bennett, Christine</surname> <given-names>I</given-names></author> <author><surname>.</surname></author> <title>Comprehensive multicultural education: theory and practice</title>. <volume>4.Auflage</volume>, <other>Boston</other>: <publisher>Allyn</publisher> and Bacon <year>1999</year>.<raw>Bennett, Christine I .: Comprehensive multicultural education: theory and practice. 4.Auflage, Boston: Allyn and Bacon, 1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bennett, Milton</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></author>.: „<title>Toward ethnorelativism: A developmental model of intercultural sensivity</title>“, in: <editor>R. Michael Paige</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Education for</source> <title>the intercultural experience</title>. <other>Yarmouth, ME</other> <publisher>Intercultural Press</publisher> <year>1993</year>, S. <fpage>21</fpage> - <lpage>71</lpage>.<raw>Bennett, Milton J.: „Toward ethnorelativism: A developmental model of intercultural sensivity“, in: R. Michael Paige (Hrsg.): Education for the intercultural experience. Yarmouth, ME: Intercultural Press, 1993, S. 21-71.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Benson, Beverly</surname></author> et al. „<title>A combined basic writing/English as a second language class: melting pot or mishmash</title>?“ in: <source>Journal of Basic Writing</source> <volume>11(1</volume>), <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>58</fpage> - <lpage>73</lpage>.<raw>Benson, Beverly, et al.: „A combined basic writing/English as a second language class: melting pot or mishmash?“ in: Journal of Basic Writing 11(1), 1992, S. 58-73.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bhabha</surname>, <given-names>Homi K.</given-names></author> „<title>Post-colonial authority and post-modern guilt</title>“, in: <editor>Lawrence Grossberg, Cary Nelson</editor> & <author><surname>Paula</surname></author> <title>Treichler: Cultural Studies</title>. <other>London</other>: <publisher>Routledge</publisher>, <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>56</fpage> - <lpage>66</lpage>.<raw>Bhabha, Homi K.: „Post-colonial authority and post-modern guilt“, in: Lawrence Grossberg, Cary Nelson & Paula Treichler: Cultural Studies. London: Routledge, 1992, S. 56-66.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bliesener, Ulrich</surname> <given-names>„A</given-names></author> <author><surname>European</surname></author> <title>View of English Instruction</title>“, in: <source>TESOL Matters 10(4)</source> <year>2000</year> [Online] <url>http://www.tesol.org/pubs/articles/tm0010-11.html</url> (<other>2.3.2001</other>).<raw>Bliesener, Ulrich: „A European View of English Instruction“, in: TESOL Matters 10(4), 2000 [Online] http://www.tesol.org/pubs/articles/tm0010-11.html (2.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bludau</surname>, <given-names>Michael</given-names></author>: „<title>Zum Stand des bilingualen Unterrichts in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland</title>“, in: <source>Neusprachliche Mitteilungen</source> <volume>49(4</volume>), <year>1996</year>, S. <fpage>208</fpage> - <lpage>215</lpage>.<raw>Bludau, Michael: „Zum Stand des bilingualen Unterrichts in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland“, in: Neusprachliche Mitteilungen, 49(4), 1996, S. 208-215.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bredella</surname>, <given-names>Lothar</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Christ</surname>, <given-names>Herbert</given-names></author>: „<title>Didaktik des Fremdverstehens im Rahmen einer Theorie des Lehrens und Lernens fremder Sprachen</title>“, in: <editor>Lothar Bredella</editor> & <editor>Herbert Christ</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Didaktik des Fremdverstehens</source> <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Gunter Narr</publisher> <year>1995</year>, S. <fpage>8</fpage> - <lpage>19</lpage>.<raw>Bredella, Lothar & Christ, Herbert: „Didaktik des Fremdverstehens im Rahmen einer Theorie des Lehrens und Lernens fremder Sprachen“, in: Lothar Bredella & Herbert Christ (Hrsg.): Didaktik des Fremdverstehens. Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 1995, S. 8-19.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bredella</surname>, <given-names>Lothar</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Delanoy</surname>, <given-names>Werner</given-names></author>: „<title>Was ist interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>?“, in: <editor>Lothar Bredella</editor> & <title>Werner Delanoy: Interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>. <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Gunter Narr</publisher> <year>1999</year>, S. <fpage>11</fpage> - <lpage>31</lpage><raw>Bredella, Lothar & Delanoy, Werner: „Was ist interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht?“, in: Lothar Bredella & Werner Delanoy: Interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht. Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 1999, S. 11-31</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bredella</surname>, <given-names>Lothar</given-names></author>: „<title>Zielsetzungen interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterrichts</title>“, in <editor>Lothar Bredella</editor> & <title>Werner Delanoy: Interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>. <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Gunter Narr</publisher> <year>1999</year>, S. <fpage>85</fpage> - <lpage>120</lpage>.<raw>Bredella, Lothar: „Zielsetzungen interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterrichts“, in Lothar Bredella & Werner Delanoy: Interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht. Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 1999, S. 85-120.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Brooks</surname>, <given-names>Nelson</given-names></author>: „<title>Teaching Culture in the Foreign Language Classroom</title>“, in: <source>Foreign Language Annals</source> <volume>1(3</volume>), <year>1968</year>, S. <fpage>204</fpage> - <lpage>217</lpage>.<raw>Brooks, Nelson: „Teaching Culture in the Foreign Language Classroom“, in: Foreign Language Annals 1(3), 1968, S. 204-217.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bryam</surname>, <given-names>Michael</given-names></author>: „<title>Learning Language without a Culture? The case of English as a lingua franca</title>“, in: <editor>Lothar Bredella, Franz-Joseph Meißner, Ansgar Nünning</editor> & <editor>Dietmar Rösler</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Wie ist Fremdverstehen</source> <title>lehr- und lernbar</title>? <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Gunter Narr</publisher> <year>2000</year>, S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <lpage>17</lpage>.<raw>Bryam, Michael: „Learning Language without a Culture? The case of English as a lingua franca“, in: Lothar Bredella, Franz-Joseph Meißner, Ansgar Nünning & Dietmar Rösler (Hrsg.): Wie ist Fremdverstehen lehr- und lernbar?  Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 2000, S. 1-17.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Burger</surname>, <given-names>Günter</given-names></author>: „<title>Englisch als globale lingua franca: Überlegungen zu einer notwendigen Neuorientierung des Englischunterrichts</title>“, in: <source>Fremdsprachenunterricht 1/2000</source> S. <fpage>9</fpage> - <lpage>14</lpage>.<raw>Burger, Günter: „Englisch als globale lingua franca: Überlegungen zu einer notwendigen Neuorientierung des Englischunterrichts“, in: Fremdsprachenunterricht 1/2000, S. 9-14.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Buttjes</surname>, <given-names>Dieter</given-names></author>: „<title>Didaktische Theorie der Landeskunde. Zur Integration des landeskundlichen Lernens in den Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>“, in: <editor>Dieter Buttjes</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Landeskundliches Lernen im Englischunterricht. Zur Theorie und Praxis des inhaltsorientierten Fremdsprachenunterricht</source> <other>Paderborn et al.: Schöningh</other> <year>1980</year>, S. <fpage>10</fpage> - <lpage>29</lpage><raw>Buttjes, Dieter: „Didaktische Theorie der Landeskunde. Zur Integration des landeskundlichen Lernens in den Fremdsprachenunterricht“, in: Dieter Buttjes (Hrsg.): Landeskundliches Lernen im Englischunterricht. Zur Theorie und Praxis des inhaltsorientierten Fremdsprachenunterricht. Paderborn et al.: Schöningh, 1980, S. 10-29</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Buttjes</surname>, <given-names>Dieter</given-names></author>: „<title>Interkulturelles Lernen im Englischunterricht</title>“, in: <source>Der fremdsprachliche Unterricht</source> <year>1/1991</year>, S. <fpage>2</fpage> - <lpage>8</lpage>.<raw>Buttjes, Dieter: „Interkulturelles Lernen im Englischunterricht“, in: Der fremdsprachliche Unterricht, 1/1991, S. 2-8.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Buttjes</surname>, <given-names>Dieter</given-names></author>: „<title>Landeskunde-Didaktik und landeskundliches Curriculum</title>“ in: <editor>Karl- Richard Bausch</editor> <other>et al</other> (Hrsg.): <source>Handbuch Fremdsprachenunterricht. 3. überarbeitete und erweiterte Auflage</source> <other>Tübingen/Basel: Francke</other> <year>1995</year>, S. <fpage>142</fpage> - <lpage>149</lpage>.<raw>Buttjes, Dieter: „Landeskunde-Didaktik und landeskundliches Curriculum“ in: Karl- Richard Bausch et al. (Hrsg.): Handbuch Fremdsprachenunterricht. 3. überarbeitete und erweiterte Auflage. Tübingen/Basel: Francke, 1995, S. 142-149.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Buttjes</surname>, <given-names>Dieter</given-names></author>: „<title>Lernziel Kulturkompetenz</title>“, in: <editor>Gerhard Bach</editor> & <editor>Johannes Peter Timm</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Englischunterricht. 2. überarbeitete und erweiterte Auflage</source> <other>Tübingen: Francke</other> <year>1996</year>, S. <fpage>69</fpage> - <lpage>102</lpage>.<raw>Buttjes, Dieter: „Lernziel Kulturkompetenz“, in: Gerhard Bach & Johannes Peter Timm (Hrsg.): Englischunterricht. 2. überarbeitete und erweiterte Auflage. Tübingen: Francke, 1996, S. 69-102.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Caspari</surname>, <given-names>Daniela</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Zydatiß</surname>, <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names></author>: “<title>Mehrsprachigkeit in die Schule: English avant tout</title>?”, in: <source>Fremdsprachenunterricht 1/2000</source> S. <fpage>5</fpage> - <lpage>8</lpage>.<raw>Caspari, Daniela & Zydatiß, Wolfgang: “Mehrsprachigkeit in die Schule: English avant tout?”, in: Fremdsprachenunterricht 1/2000, S. 5-8.</raw></sequence><sequence><editor>Center</editor> for <title>Advanced Research on Language Acquisition “Culture and Language Learning: What is Culture</title>?” [Online] <url>http://carla.acad.umn.edu/culture.html</url> (<other>2.3.2001</other>).<raw>Center for Advanced Research on Language Acquisition “Culture and Language Learning: What is Culture?” [Online] http://carla.acad.umn.edu/culture.html (2.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Chowan</surname>, <given-names>Todd</given-names></author>: “<title>Key Concepts of Successful Immersion</title>”, in: <editor>American Council on Immersion</editor> <source>Education Newsletter [Online], 1/1997</source> <url>http://carla.acad.umn.edu/acie- news.tips.html</url> (<other>5.3.2001</other>).<raw>Chowan, Todd: “Key Concepts of Successful Immersion”, in: American Council on Immersion Education Newsletter [Online], 1/1997. http://carla.acad.umn.edu/acie- news.tips.html (5.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Christ</surname>, <given-names>Herbert</given-names></author>: „<title>Fremdverstehen und interkulturelles Lernen</title>“, in: <source>Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 3/1996, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/christ.htm</source> (<year>4.3.2001</year>).<raw>Christ, Herbert: „Fremdverstehen und interkulturelles Lernen“, in: Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 3/1996, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/christ.htm (4.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Cushner</surname>, <given-names>Kenneth</given-names></author>: „<title>Intercultural Education from an International Perspective: Commonalities and Future Prospects</title>”, in: <editor>Kenneth Cushner</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>International Perspectives on Intercultural Education</source> <other>Mahwah, New Jersey</other> <publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher> <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>353</fpage> - <lpage>370</lpage>.<raw>Cushner, Kenneth: „Intercultural Education from an International Perspective: Commonalities and Future Prospects”, in: Kenneth Cushner (Hrsg.): International Perspectives on Intercultural Education. Mahwah, New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1998, S. 353-370.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Cushner</surname>, <given-names>Kenneth</given-names></author>: „<title>Intercultural Education from an International Perspective: An Introduction</title>”, in: <editor>Kenneth Cushner</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>International Perspectives on Intercultural Education</source> <other>Mahwah, New Jersey</other> <publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher> <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <lpage>13</lpage>.<raw>Cushner, Kenneth: „Intercultural Education from an International Perspective: An Introduction”, in: Kenneth Cushner (Hrsg.): International Perspectives on Intercultural Education. Mahwah, New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1998, S. 1-13.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>De Florio-Hansen</surname> <given-names>Inez</given-names></author>: „<title>Interkulturalität als Voraussetzung für personale Autonomie und Authentizität</title>“, in: <source>Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts</source> <year>3/2000</year>, S. <fpage>227</fpage> - <lpage>234</lpage>.<raw>De Florio-Hansen, Inez: „Interkulturalität als Voraussetzung für personale Autonomie und Authentizität“, in: Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts 3/2000, S. 227-234.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Doyé</surname>, <given-names>Peter</given-names></author>: „<title>English as a global language. Implications for the cultural content of teaching and learning</title>”, in: <editor>Claus Gnutzmann</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Teaching and</source> <title>learning English as a Global language: native and non-native perspectives</title>. <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Stauffenburg</publisher>, <year>1999</year>, S. <fpage>93</fpage> - <lpage>105</lpage>.<raw>Doyé, Peter: „English as a global language. Implications for the cultural content of teaching and learning”, in: Claus Gnutzmann (Hrsg.): Teaching and learning English as a Global language: native and non-native perspectives. Tübingen: Stauffenburg, 1999, S. 93-105.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Einhoff</surname>, <given-names>Jürgen</given-names></author>: „<title>Der interkulturelle Ansatz - Denkanstoßfür die Textaufgabe? Zur Frage der Konsequenzen des interkulturellen Ansatzes für die schriftliche Textarbeit</title>“, in: <source>Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts</source> <year>3/1993</year>, S. <fpage>248</fpage> - <lpage>256</lpage>.<raw>Einhoff, Jürgen: „Der interkulturelle Ansatz - Denkanstoßfür die Textaufgabe? Zur Frage der Konsequenzen des interkulturellen Ansatzes für die schriftliche Textarbeit“, in: Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts 3/1993, S. 248-256.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Elderling</surname>, <given-names>Lotty</given-names></author>: „<title>Multiculturalism and multicultural education in an international perspective</title>“, in: <source>Anthropology and Education Quarterly</source> <volume>27(3</volume>), <year>1996</year>, S. <fpage>315</fpage> - <lpage>330</lpage>.<raw>Elderling, Lotty: „Multiculturalism and multicultural education in an international perspective“, in: Anthropology and Education Quarterly, 27(3), 1996, S. 315-330.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Ferdman</surname>, <given-names>Bernardo M.</given-names></author> „<title>Literacy and Cultural Identity</title>“, in: <editor>Masahiko Minami</editor> & <editor>Bruce P. Kennedy</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Language Issues in Literacy and Bilingual/Multicultural Education. Reprint Series</source> Bd.22, Cambridge <source>Harvard Educational Review</source> <year>1991</year>, S. <fpage>347</fpage> - <lpage>371</lpage>.<raw>Ferdman, Bernardo M.: „Literacy and Cultural Identity“, in: Masahiko Minami & Bruce P. Kennedy (Hrsg.): Language Issues in Literacy and Bilingual/Multicultural Education. Reprint Series, Bd.22, Cambridge: Harvard Educational Review, 1991, S. 347-371.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Ferguson</surname>, <given-names>Charles A</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Huebner</surname>, <given-names>Thom</given-names></author>: „<title>Foreign Language Instruction and Second Language Acquisition Research in the United States</title>“, in: <editor>Kees de Bot, Ralph B.Ginsberg</editor> & <editor>Claire Kramsch</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Foreign Language Research</source> in <title>Cross-Cultural Perspective</title>. <other>Amsterdam</other>: <publisher>John Benjamins</publisher> <year>1991</year>, S. <fpage>3</fpage> - <lpage>19</lpage>.<raw>Ferguson, Charles A. & Huebner, Thom: „Foreign Language Instruction and Second Language Acquisition Research in the United States“, in: Kees de Bot, Ralph B.Ginsberg & Claire Kramsch (Hrsg.): Foreign Language Research in Cross-Cultural Perspective. Amsterdam: John Benjamins, 1991, S. 3-19.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Finkbeiner</surname>, <given-names>Claudia</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Koplin</surname>, <given-names>Christine</given-names></author>: „<title>Handlungsorientiert Fremdverstehen lernen und lehren</title>“, in: <source>Fremdsprachenunterricht</source> <year>4/2000</year>, S. <fpage>254</fpage> - <lpage>261</lpage>.<raw>Finkbeiner, Claudia & Koplin, Christine: „Handlungsorientiert Fremdverstehen lernen und lehren“, in: Fremdsprachenunterricht 4/2000, S. 254-261.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fortune</surname>, <given-names>Tara</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Jorstad</surname>, <given-names>Helen L.</given-names></author> „<title>U.S. immersion programs: a national survey</title>“, in: <source>Foreign Language Annals</source> <volume>29</volume> (<issue>3</issue>), S. <fpage>163</fpage> - <lpage>190</lpage>.<raw>Fortune, Tara & Jorstad, Helen L.: „U.S. immersion programs: a national survey“, in: Foreign Language Annals, 29 (3), S. 163-190.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Gay</surname>, <given-names>Geneva</given-names></author>: <title>Culturally responsive teaching: theory research, and practice</title>. <source>Multicultural Education Series</source> <other>New York</other> <publisher>Teachers College Press</publisher> <year>2000</year>.<raw>Gay, Geneva: Culturally responsive teaching: theory research, and practice. Multicultural Education Series, New York: Teachers College Press, 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Genesee</surname>, <given-names>Fred</given-names></author>: “<title>Integrating language and content: Lessons from immersion</title>” <source>Educational Practice Report</source> <volume>11</volume>, <year>1994</year> [Online] <url>http://www.ncbe.gwu.edu/ miscpubs/ncrcdsll/epr11.htm</url> (<other>3.3.2001</other>).<raw>Genesee, Fred: “Integrating language and content: Lessons from immersion” Educational Practice Report, 11, 1994 [Online] http://www.ncbe.gwu.edu/ miscpubs/ncrcdsll/epr11.htm (3.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Glazer</surname>, <given-names>Nathan</given-names></author>: <title>We are All Multiculturalists Now</title>. <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher> <year>1997</year>.<raw>Glazer, Nathan: We are All Multiculturalists Now. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1997.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Gnutzmann</surname>, <given-names>Claus</given-names></author>: „<title>Interkulturelles Lernen auch noch im Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>?“ in: <editor>Karl-Richard Bausch</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Interkulturelles Lernen im Fremdsprachenunterricht. Tübingen: Gunter Narr</source> <year>1994</year>, S. 63- <fpage>72</fpage>.<raw>Gnutzmann, Claus: „Interkulturelles Lernen auch noch im Fremdsprachenunterricht?“ in: Karl-Richard Bausch (Hrsg.): Interkulturelles Lernen im Fremdsprachenunterricht. Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 1994, S. 63- 72.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Gudykunst</surname>, <given-names>William B</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Kim</surname>, <given-names>Young Y.</given-names></author> <title>Communicating with Strangers: an Approach to Intercultural Communcations</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>, <year>1984</year>.<raw>Gudykunst, William B. & Kim, Young Y.: Communicating with Strangers: an Approach to Intercultural Communcations. New York: Addison-Wesley, 1984.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hallet</surname>, <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names></author>: „<title>The Bilingual Triangle</title>“, in: <source>Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts</source> <volume>45(2</volume>), <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>115</fpage> - <lpage>125</lpage>.<raw>Hallet, Wolfgang: „The Bilingual Triangle“, in: Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts, 45(2), 1998, S. 115-125.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Harklau</surname>, <given-names>Linda</given-names></author>: “<title>Representing culture in the ESL writing classroom</title>”, in: <editor>Eli Hinkel</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Culture in</source> <title>second language teaching and learning</title>. <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1999</year>, S. <fpage>109</fpage> - <lpage>130</lpage>.<raw>Harklau, Linda: “Representing culture in the ESL writing classroom”, in: Eli Hinkel (Hrsg.): Culture in second language teaching and learning. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1999, S. 109-130.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hendon</surname>, <given-names>Ursula S.</given-names></author> „<title>The Interaction of Language and Culture. New Views in Foreign Language Teaching</title>“, in: <source>Der fremdsprachliche Unterricht</source> <volume>45(1</volume>), <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>2</fpage> - <lpage>8</lpage>.<raw>Hendon, Ursula S.: „The Interaction of Language and Culture. New Views in Foreign Language Teaching“, in: Der fremdsprachliche Unterricht 45(1), 1992, S. 2-8.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hinkel</surname>, <given-names>Eli</given-names></author>: “<title>Introduction: Culture in research and second language pedagogy</title>”, in: <editor>Eli Hinkel</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Culture in</source> <title>second language teaching and learning</title>. <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1999</year>, S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <lpage>7</lpage>.<raw>Hinkel, Eli: “Introduction: Culture in research and second language pedagogy”, in: Eli Hinkel (Hrsg.): Culture in second language teaching and learning.  Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1999, S. 1-7.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hollins</surname>, <given-names>Etta R</given-names></author> & <editor>Oliver, Eileen I</editor> (Hrsg.): <title>Pathways to success in school. Culturally Responsive Teaching. Mawah</title>, <other>New Jersey</other> Lawrence Erlbaum Associates <year>1999</year>.<raw>Hollins, Etta R. & Oliver, Eileen I. (Hrsg.): Pathways to success in school. Culturally Responsive Teaching. Mawah, New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>House</surname>, <given-names>Juliane</given-names></author>: „<title>Zum Erwerb Interkultureller Kompetenz im Unterricht des Deutschen als Fremdsprache</title>“, in: <source>Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 3/1996, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/house.htm</source> (<year>5.3.2001</year>).<raw>House, Juliane: „Zum Erwerb Interkultureller Kompetenz im Unterricht des Deutschen als Fremdsprache“, in: Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 3/1996, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/house.htm (5.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Howard</surname>, <given-names>Gary R.</given-names></author> <title>We can ’ t teach what we don ’ t know: white teachers, multiracial schools</title>. <source>Multicultural Education Series</source> <other>New York</other> <publisher>Teachers College Press</publisher> <year>1999</year>.<raw>Howard, Gary R.: We can ’ t teach what we don ’ t know: white teachers, multiracial schools. Multicultural Education Series, New York: Teachers College Press, 1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hu</surname>, <given-names>Adelheid</given-names></author>: „<title>Identität und Fremdsprachenunterricht in Migrationsgesellschaften</title>“, in: <editor>Lothar Bredella</editor> & <title>Werner Delanoy: Interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>. <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Gunter Narr</publisher> <year>1999</year>, S. <fpage>209</fpage> - <lpage>239</lpage>.<raw>Hu, Adelheid: „Identität und Fremdsprachenunterricht in Migrationsgesellschaften“, in: Lothar Bredella & Werner Delanoy: Interkultureller Fremdsprachenunterricht. Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 1999, S. 209-239.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Johnson</surname>, <given-names>Robert K</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Swain</surname>, <given-names>Merrill</given-names></author>: “<title>Immersion education. A category within bilingual education</title>”, in: <editor>Robert K. Johnson</editor> & <editor>Merrill Swain</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Immersion Education: International Perspectives</source> <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1997</year>, S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <lpage>16</lpage>.<raw>Johnson, Robert K. & Swain, Merrill: “Immersion education. A category within bilingual education”, in: Robert K. Johnson & Merrill Swain (Hrsg.): Immersion Education: International Perspectives. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1997, S. 1-16.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kramsch</surname>, <given-names>Claire</given-names></author>: “<title>Global and local identities in the contact zone</title>”, in: <editor>Claus Gnutzmann</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Teaching and</source> <title>learning English as a Global language: native and non-native perspectives</title>. <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Stauffenburg</publisher>, <year>1999</year>, S. <volume>131-</volume> <fpage>143</fpage>.<raw>Kramsch, Claire: “Global and local identities in the contact zone”, in: Claus Gnutzmann (Hrsg.): Teaching and learning English as a Global language: native and non-native perspectives. Tübingen: Stauffenburg, 1999, S. 131- 143.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kramsch</surname>, <given-names>Claire</given-names></author>: “<title>The Cultural Component of Language Teaching</title>”, in: <source>Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 2/1996, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/kramsch2.htm</source> (<year>4.3.2001</year>).<raw>Kramsch, Claire: “The Cultural Component of Language Teaching”, in: Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 2/1996, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/kramsch2.htm (4.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kramsch</surname>, <given-names>Claire</given-names></author>: „<title>Culture in Language Learning: A View from the U.S</title>.“, in: <editor>Kees de Bot, Ralph B.Ginsberg</editor> & <editor>Claire Kramsch</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Foreign Language Research</source> in <title>Cross-Cultural Perspective</title>. <other>Amsterdam</other>: <publisher>John Benjamins</publisher> <year>1991</year>, S. <fpage>217</fpage> - <lpage>240</lpage>.<raw>Kramsch, Claire: „Culture in Language Learning: A View from the U.S.“, in: Kees de Bot, Ralph B.Ginsberg & Claire Kramsch (Hrsg.): Foreign Language Research in Cross-Cultural Perspective. Amsterdam: John Benjamins, 1991, S. 217-240.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kramsch</surname>, <given-names>Claire</given-names></author>: „<title>The privilege of the intercultural speaker</title>“, in: <editor>Michael Bryam</editor> & <editor>Michael Fleming</editor> (Hrsg.) <title>Language Learning in Intercultural Perspective</title>. <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>16</fpage> - <lpage>31</lpage>.<raw>Kramsch, Claire: „The privilege of the intercultural speaker“, in: Michael Bryam & Michael Fleming (Hrsg.) Language Learning in Intercultural Perspective.  Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1998, S. 16-31.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kramsch</surname>, <given-names>Claire</given-names></author>: <title>Context and Culture in Language Teaching</title>. <other>Oxford</other>, <publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher> <year>1993</year>.<raw>Kramsch, Claire: Context and Culture in Language Teaching. Oxford, Oxford University Press, 1993.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Krumm</surname>, <given-names>Hans</given-names></author> <title>-Jürgen: „Interkulturelles Lernen und interkulturelle Kommunikation</title>“, in: <editor>Karl-Richard Bausch et.al</editor> (Hrsg.) <source>Handbuch Fremdsprachenunterricht. 3.überarbeitete und erweiterte Auflage</source> <other>Tübingen/Basel: Francke</other> <year>1995</year>, S. <fpage>156</fpage> - <lpage>161</lpage>.<raw>Krumm, Hans -Jürgen: „Interkulturelles Lernen und interkulturelle Kommunikation“, in: Karl-Richard Bausch et.al. (Hrsg.) Handbuch Fremdsprachenunterricht. 3.überarbeitete und erweiterte Auflage. Tübingen/Basel: Francke, 1995, S. 156-161.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Ladson-Billings</surname>, <given-names>Gloria</given-names></author>: „<title>But That’s Just Good Teaching! The Case for culturally relevant pedagogy</title>“, in: <source>Theory into Practice</source> <volume>34(3</volume>), <year>1995</year>, S. <fpage>161</fpage> - <lpage>165</lpage>.<raw>Ladson-Billings, Gloria: „But That’s Just Good Teaching! The Case for culturally relevant pedagogy“, in: Theory into Practice, 34(3), 1995, S. 161-165.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lange</surname>, <given-names>Dale L.</given-names></author> „<title>Response to the Welles and James Article: ACTFL Newsletter</title>, Vol. <volume>XI. No.1”</volume> in: <source>ACTFL Newsletter, Summer 1999</source> [Online] <url>http://www.actfl.org/public/articles/Summer1999.pdf</url> (<other>4.3.2001</other>), S. <fpage>9</fpage> - <lpage>11</lpage>.<raw>Lange, Dale L.: „Response to the Welles and James Article: ACTFL Newsletter, Vol. XI. No.1” in: ACTFL Newsletter, Summer 1999, [Online] http://www.actfl.org/public/articles/Summer1999.pdf (4.3.2001), S. 9-11.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Mantle-Bromley</surname>, <given-names>Corinne</given-names></author>: „<title>Preparing Students for Meanigful Culture Learning</title>“, in: <source>Foreign Language Annals</source> <volume>25(2</volume>), <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>117</fpage> - <lpage>127</lpage>.<raw>Mantle-Bromley, Corinne: „Preparing Students for Meanigful Culture Learning“, in: Foreign Language Annals 25(2), 1992, S. 117-127.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Met</surname>, <given-names>Myriam</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Lorenz</surname>, <given-names>Eileen B.</given-names></author> „<title>Lessons from U.S. immersion programs</title>“, in: <editor>Robert K. Johnson</editor> & <editor>Merrill Swain</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Immersion Education: International Perspectives</source> <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1997</year>, S. <fpage>243</fpage> - <lpage>264</lpage>.<raw>Met, Myriam & Lorenz, Eileen B.: „Lessons from U.S. immersion programs“, in: Robert K. Johnson & Merrill Swain (Hrsg.): Immersion Education: International Perspectives. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1997, S. 243-264.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Meyer</surname>, <given-names>Meinert A.</given-names></author> „<title>Negotiating of Meaning. Der Versuch einer handlungsorientierten Verknüpfung von Landeskunde und Politik im Englischunterricht (Sek. II</title>)“, in: <source>Der fremdsprachliche Unterricht</source> <volume>26(3</volume>), <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>16</fpage> - <lpage>21</lpage>.<raw>Meyer, Meinert A.: „Negotiating of Meaning. Der Versuch einer handlungsorientierten Verknüpfung von Landeskunde und Politik im Englischunterricht (Sek. II)“, in: Der fremdsprachliche Unterricht, 26(3), 1992, S. 16-21.</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Ministerium für Schule und Weiterbildung, Wissenschaft und Forschung des</title> <editor>Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Richtlinien und Lehrpläne für die Sekundarstufe II - Gymnasium / Gesamtschule in Nordrhein-Westfalen. Englisch</source> <other>Frechen</other>: <publisher>Ritterbach</publisher>, <year>1999</year>.<raw>Ministerium für Schule und Weiterbildung, Wissenschaft und Forschung des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen (Hrsg.): Richtlinien und Lehrpläne für die Sekundarstufe II - Gymnasium / Gesamtschule in Nordrhein-Westfalen. Englisch. Frechen: Ritterbach, 1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Norment</surname> <given-names>Jr</given-names></author>., <author><surname>Nathaniel</surname></author>: “<title>Some Effects of Culture-Referenced Topics on the Writ ing Performance of African American Students</title>”, in: <source>Journal of Basic Writing 16(2)</source> <year>1997</year>, S. <fpage>17</fpage> - <lpage>45</lpage>.<raw>Norment Jr., Nathaniel: “Some Effects of Culture-Referenced Topics on the Writ ing Performance of African American Students”, in: Journal of Basic Writing 16(2), 1997, S. 17-45.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Nostrand</surname>, <given-names>Howard L.</given-names></author> „<title>The Emergent Model</title>“, in: <source>American Foreign Language Teacher</source> <volume>4(3</volume>), <year>1974</year>, S. <fpage>23</fpage> - <lpage>27</lpage>.<raw>Nostrand, Howard L.: „The Emergent Model“, in: American Foreign Language Teacher 4(3), 1974, S. 23-27.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Nünning</surname>, <given-names>Vera</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Nünning</surname>, <given-names>Ansgar</given-names></author>: „<title>British Cultural Studies konkret. 10 Leitkonzepte für einen innovativen Kulturunterricht</title>“, in: <source>Der Fremdsprachliche Unterricht</source> <year>1/2000</year>, S. <fpage>4</fpage> - <lpage>10</lpage>.<raw>Nünning, Vera & Nünning, Ansgar: „British Cultural Studies konkret. 10 Leitkonzepte für einen innovativen Kulturunterricht“, in: Der Fremdsprachliche Unterricht 1/2000, S. 4-10.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Patthey-Chavez</surname>, <given-names>G. Genevieve</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Gergen</surname>, <given-names>Constance A.</given-names></author> “<title>Culture as an Instructional Resource in the Multiethnic Composition Classroom</title>”, in: <source>Journal of Basic Writing</source> <year>1/1992</year>, S. <fpage>75</fpage> - <lpage>96</lpage>.<raw>Patthey-Chavez, G. Genevieve & Gergen, Constance A.: “Culture as an Instructional Resource in the Multiethnic Composition Classroom”, in: Journal of Basic Writing 1/1992, S. 75-96.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Pauels</surname>, <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names></author>: „<title>Interkulturelles Lernen - die neue Herausforderung im Fremdsprachenunterricht</title>“, in: <source>Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts</source> <year>4/1993</year>, S. <fpage>341</fpage> - <lpage>348</lpage>.<raw>Pauels, Wolfgang: „Interkulturelles Lernen - die neue Herausforderung im Fremdsprachenunterricht“, in: Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts 4/1993, S. 341-348.</raw></sequence><sequence><editor>Paula Heusinkveld</editor> (Hrsg.): <source>Pathways to Culture</source> <other>Yarmouth</other>: <publisher>Intercultural Press</publisher> <year>1997</year>.<raw>Paula Heusinkveld (Hrsg.): Pathways to Culture. Yarmouth: Intercultural Press, 1997.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Paules</surname>, <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names></author>: „<title>Language Diversity and Cultural Identity in the USA - A European View of a Controversy</title>“, in: <source>Zeitschrift für Anglistik und Amerikanistik</source> <volume>46.3</volume>, <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>193</fpage> - <lpage>203</lpage>.<raw>Paules, Wolfgang: „Language Diversity and Cultural Identity in the USA - A European View of a Controversy“, in: Zeitschrift für Anglistik und Amerikanistik, 46.3, 1998, S. 193-203.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Pérez</surname>, <given-names>Bertha</given-names></author>: „<title>Literacy, Diversity, and Programmatic Responses</title>“, in: <editor>Bertha Pérez</editor> et al. <title>Sociocultural contexts of language and literacy</title>. <other>Mahwah, New Jersey</other> <publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher> <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>3</fpage> - <lpage>20</lpage>.<raw>Pérez, Bertha: „Literacy, Diversity, and Programmatic Responses“, in: Bertha Pérez et al.: Sociocultural contexts of language and literacy. Mahwah, New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1998, S. 3-20.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Raddatz</surname>, <given-names>Volker</given-names></author>: <title>Englandkunde im Wandel deutscher Erziehungsziele 1886-1945</title>. Kronberg: Scriptor <year>1977</year>.<raw>Raddatz, Volker: Englandkunde im Wandel deutscher Erziehungsziele 1886-1945.  Kronberg: Scriptor, 1977.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Rhodes</surname>, <given-names>Nancy C.</given-names></author> <author><surname>Christian</surname>, <given-names>Donna</given-names></author> & <author><surname>Barfield</surname>, <given-names>Susan</given-names></author>: “<title>Innovations in immersion. The Key School two-way model</title>”, in: <editor>Robert K. Johnson</editor> & <editor>Merrill Swain</editor> (Hrsg .) <source>Immersion Education: International Perspectives</source> <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1997</year>, S. <fpage>265</fpage> - <lpage>283</lpage>.<raw>Rhodes, Nancy C., Christian, Donna & Barfield, Susan: “Innovations in immersion. The Key School two-way model”, in: Robert K. Johnson & Merrill Swain (Hrsg .): Immersion Education: International Perspectives. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1997, S. 265-283.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Risager</surname>, <given-names>Karen</given-names></author>: “<title>Language Teaching and the Process of European Integration</title>”, in: <editor>Michael Bryam</editor> & <editor>Michael Fleming</editor> (Hrsg.) <title>Language Learning in Intercultural Perspective</title>. <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher> <year>1998</year>, S. <fpage>242</fpage> - <lpage>254</lpage>.<raw>Risager, Karen: “Language Teaching and the Process of European Integration”, in: Michael Bryam & Michael Fleming (Hrsg.) Language Learning in Intercultural Perspective. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1998, S. 242-254.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Robinson</surname>, <given-names>Gail L</given-names></author> <author><surname>Nemetz</surname></author>: „<title>The-Magic-Carpet-Ride-to-Another-Culture Syndrome: An International Perspektive</title>“, in: <source>Foreign language Annals</source> <volume>11(2</volume>), <year>1978</year>, S. <fpage>135</fpage> - <lpage>146</lpage>.<raw>Robinson, Gail L. Nemetz: „The-Magic-Carpet-Ride-to-Another-Culture Syndrome: An International Perspektive“, in: Foreign language Annals 11(2), 1978, S. 135-146.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Robinson</surname>, <given-names>Gail L</given-names></author> <author><surname>Nemetz</surname></author>: <title>Crosscultural Understanding</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>Pergamon</publisher>, <year>1985</year>.<raw>Robinson, Gail L. Nemetz: Crosscultural Understanding. New York: Pergamon, 1985.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Schulz</surname>, <given-names>Renate</given-names></author>: „<title>Der Fremdsprachenunterricht in den Vereinigten Staaten: Tendenzen und Herausforderungen</title>“, in: <source>Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 3/1999, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/schulz5.htm</source> (<year>5.3.2001</year>).<raw>Schulz, Renate: „Der Fremdsprachenunterricht in den Vereinigten Staaten: Tendenzen und Herausforderungen“, in: Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 3/1999, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/schulz5.htm (5.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Seelye</surname>, <given-names>H.Ned</given-names></author>: „<title>The Cultural Mazeway: Six Organizing Goals“, in: Teaching Culture: Strategies for Intercultural Communication</title>. <volume>3</volume>. <other>Auflage, Lincolnwood</other> <publisher>National Textbooko</publisher> <year>1993</year>, S. <fpage>26</fpage> - <lpage>34</lpage>.<raw>Seelye, H.Ned: „The Cultural Mazeway: Six Organizing Goals“, in: Teaching Culture: Strategies for Intercultural Communication. 3. Auflage, Lincolnwood: National Textbooko, 1993, S. 26-34.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Shaughnessy</surname>, <given-names>Mina P.</given-names></author> <title>Errors and Expectations. A guide for the teacher of basic writing</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher> <year>1976</year>.<raw>Shaughnessy, Mina P.: Errors and Expectations. A guide for the teacher of basic writing. New York: Oxford University Press, 1976.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stern</surname>, <given-names>H. H.</given-names></author> <title>Issues and Options in Language Teaching</title>. <other>Oxford</other>: <publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher> <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>205</fpage> - <lpage>236</lpage>.<raw>Stern, H. H.: Issues and Options in Language Teaching. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1992, S. 205-236.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stimpson</surname>, <given-names>Catherine R.</given-names></author> “<title>Introduction to: Who’s Art Is It</title>?”, in: <editor>Jane Kramer</editor> <title>Whose Art Is It</title>? <other>Durham</other>: <publisher>Duke University Press</publisher> <year>1994</year>, S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <lpage>35</lpage>.<raw>Stimpson, Catherine R.: “Introduction to: Who’s Art Is It?”, in: Jane Kramer: Whose Art Is It? Durham: Duke University Press, 1994, S. 1-35.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Tedick</surname>, <given-names>Diane J.</given-names></author> “<title>Immersion in the K-12 Context“, American Council on Immersion Education Newsletter [Online], 1/1997</title>. <url>http://carla.acad.umn.edu/acie- news.K12.html</url> (<other>5.3.2001</other>).<raw>Tedick, Diane J.: “Immersion in the K-12 Context“, American Council on Immersion Education Newsletter [Online], 1/1997. http://carla.acad.umn.edu/acie- news.K12.html (5.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Thomas</surname>, <given-names>Alexander</given-names></author> &, <author><surname>Wagner</surname>, <given-names>Karl Heinz</given-names></author> „<title>Didaktische Grundlagen und methodische Anregungen zum interkulturellen Lernen im Englischunterricht</title>“, in: <source>Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts</source> <year>4/2000</year>, S. <fpage>355</fpage> - <lpage>363</lpage>.<raw>Thomas, Alexander, & Wagner, Karl Heinz: „Didaktische Grundlagen und methodische Anregungen zum interkulturellen Lernen im Englischunterricht“, in: Praxis des neusprachlichen Unterrichts 4/2000, S. 355-363.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Thomas</surname>, <given-names>Christian</given-names></author>: „<title>Interkulturalität, Pragmalinguistik und Kritische Kompetenz in neuen DaF-Lehrwerken</title>. <source>Fallbeispiel: Die Suche</source> <volume>2</volume> “, in <source>Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 1/1998, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/thomas2.htm</source> (<year>3.3.2001</year>).<raw>Thomas, Christian: „Interkulturalität, Pragmalinguistik und Kritische Kompetenz in neuen DaF-Lehrwerken. Fallbeispiel: Die Suche 2 “, in: Zeitschrift für Interkulturellen Fremdsprachenunterricht [Online], 1/1998, http://www.ualberta.ca/~german/ejournal/thomas2.htm (3.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Thürmann</surname>, <given-names>Eike</given-names></author>: „<title>Fremdsprachenunterricht, Landeskunde und interkulturelle Erziehung</title>“, in: <source>Die Neuren Sprachen</source> <volume>93(4</volume>), <year>1994</year>, S. <fpage>316</fpage> - <lpage>334</lpage>.<raw>Thürmann, Eike: „Fremdsprachenunterricht, Landeskunde und interkulturelle Erziehung“, in: Die Neuren Sprachen 93(4), 1994, S. 316-334.</raw></sequence><sequence><editor>University of Hawaii</editor> „<title>Benefits of being bilingual</title>“. [Online] <url>http://www.lll.hawaii.edu/web/haw/immersion/seclang.html</url> (<other>29.3.2001</other>).<raw>University of Hawaii: „Benefits of being bilingual“. [Online] http://www.lll.hawaii.edu/web/haw/immersion/seclang.html (29.3.2001).</raw></sequence><sequence><editor>Vollmer, Helmut</editor> (Hrsg.): <title>Multikulturelle Gesellschaft und Minderheiten: Kanada und USA</title>. <source>Beiträge zur Kanadistik</source> Band <volume>3</volume>. <other>Augsburg</other>: <publisher>AV-Verlag</publisher>, <year>1992</year>.<raw>Vollmer, Helmut (Hrsg.): Multikulturelle Gesellschaft und Minderheiten: Kanada und USA. Beiträge zur Kanadistik, Band 3. Augsburg: AV-Verlag, 1992.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Vollmer</surname>, <given-names>Helmut</given-names></author>: „<title>Diskurslernen und Kommunikationsfähigkeit. Der Beitrag der Pragmalinguistik und der Diskursanalyse zu einem erweiterten Sprachlernkonzept</title>“, in: <editor>Lothar Bredella</editor> <title>Verstehen und Verständigung durch Sprachenlernen? Fremdsprachenunterricht in einem zukünftigen Europa</title>. <other>Bochum</other>: <publisher>Brockmeyer</publisher>, <year>1995</year>, S. <fpage>104</fpage> - <lpage>127</lpage>.<raw>Vollmer, Helmut: „Diskurslernen und Kommunikationsfähigkeit. Der Beitrag der Pragmalinguistik und der Diskursanalyse zu einem erweiterten Sprachlernkonzept“, in: Lothar Bredella: Verstehen und Verständigung durch Sprachenlernen? Fremdsprachenunterricht in einem zukünftigen Europa. Bochum: Brockmeyer, 1995, S. 104-127.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Vollmer</surname>, <given-names>Helmut</given-names></author>: „<title>Englisch und Mehrsprachigkeit: Interkulturelles Lernen durch Englisch als lingua franca</title>?“, in: <editor>Dagmar Abendroth-Timmer</editor> & <editor>Gerhard Bach: Mehrsprachiges Europa. Festschrift für Michael Wendt</editor> <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Gunter Narr</publisher> <year>2001</year>, S. <fpage>91</fpage> - <lpage>110</lpage>.<raw>Vollmer, Helmut: „Englisch und Mehrsprachigkeit: Interkulturelles Lernen durch Englisch als lingua franca?“, in: Dagmar Abendroth-Timmer & Gerhard Bach: Mehrsprachiges Europa. Festschrift für Michael Wendt. Tübingen: Gunter Narr, 2001, S. 91-110.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Vollmer</surname>, <given-names>Helmut</given-names></author>: „<title>Immersion und alternative Ansätze des bilingualen Unterrichts und des Fremdsprachenerwerbs in Nordamerika - Probleme des Transfers in die Bundesrepublik Deutschland</title>,” in: <source>Zeitschrift für Fremdsprachenforschung</source> <volume>3(2</volume>), <year>1992</year>, S. <fpage>5</fpage> - <lpage>38</lpage>.<raw>Vollmer, Helmut: „Immersion und alternative Ansätze des bilingualen Unterrichts und des Fremdsprachenerwerbs in Nordamerika - Probleme des Transfers in die Bundesrepublik Deutschland,” in: Zeitschrift für Fremdsprachenforschung, 3(2), 1992, S. 5-38.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Webber</surname>, <given-names>Mark J.</given-names></author> “<title>The Role of Culture in a Competence-Based Syllabus</title>”, in: <source>Theory into Practice</source> <volume>26</volume>, <year>1987</year>, <fpage>251</fpage> - <lpage>257</lpage>.<raw>Webber, Mark J.: “The Role of Culture in a Competence-Based Syllabus”, in: Theory into Practice, 26, 1987, 251-257.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Weller</surname>, <given-names>Franz-Rudolf</given-names></author>: „<title>Bilingual oder Zweisprachig? Kritische Anmerkungen zu den Möglichkeiten und Grenzen fremdsprachigen Sachunterrichts</title>“, in: <source>Die neueren Sprachen 92(1/2)</source> <year>1993</year>, S. <fpage>8</fpage> - <lpage>22</lpage>.<raw>Weller, Franz-Rudolf: „Bilingual oder Zweisprachig? Kritische Anmerkungen zu den Möglichkeiten und Grenzen fremdsprachigen Sachunterrichts“, in: Die neueren Sprachen 92(1/2), 1993, S. 8-22.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Welles</surname>, <given-names>Elizabeth</given-names></author>: „<title>Standards for Foreign Language Learning: Implications and Perceptions</title>“ in: <source>ACTFL Newsletter</source> <other>Fall</other> <year>1998</year>, [Online] <url>http://www.actfl.org/public/articles/Fall1998-1.pdf</url> (<other>1.3.2001</other>), S. <fpage>7</fpage> - <lpage>9</lpage>.<raw>Welles, Elizabeth: „Standards for Foreign Language Learning: Implications and Perceptions“ in: ACTFL Newsletter, Fall 1998, [Online] http://www.actfl.org/public/articles/Fall1998-1.pdf (1.3.2001), S. 7-9.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Weskamp</surname>, <given-names>Ralf</given-names></author>: <title>Fachdidaktik: Grundlagen und Konzepte - Anglistik Amerikanistik</title>. <other>Berlin</other>: <publisher>Cornelsen</publisher>, <year>2001</year>.<raw>Weskamp, Ralf: Fachdidaktik: Grundlagen und Konzepte - Anglistik Amerikanistik.  Berlin: Cornelsen, 2001.</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Ich versichere, dass ich diese schriftliche Hausarbeit einschließlich beigefügter Zeichnungen, Kartenskizzen und Darstellungen selbständig verfasst und keine anderen als die angegebenen Quellen und Hilfsmittel benutzt habe. Alle Stellen dieser Arbeit, die dem Wortlaut oder dem Sinne nach anderen Werken entnommen sind, habe ich in jedem einzelnen Fall unter Angabe der Quelle deutlich als Entlehnung kenntlich gemacht</title>.<raw>Ich versichere, dass ich diese schriftliche Hausarbeit einschließlich beigefügter Zeichnungen, Kartenskizzen und Darstellungen selbständig verfasst und keine anderen als die angegebenen Quellen und Hilfsmittel benutzt habe. Alle Stellen dieser Arbeit, die dem Wortlaut oder dem Sinne nach anderen Werken entnommen sind, habe ich in jedem einzelnen Fall unter Angabe der Quelle deutlich als Entlehnung kenntlich gemacht.</raw></sequence><sequence><other>Bonn</other>, <year>29.April 2001</year> ___________________________________<raw>Bonn, 29.April 2001 ___________________________________</raw></sequence><sequence><editor>Kai Harald Vrancken</editor><raw>Kai Harald Vrancken</raw></sequence>