<sequence><author><surname>Billot</surname>, <given-names>M.-F</given-names></author>.: <author><surname>Sanctuaire</surname></author> <title>et cultes d’Athéna à Argos</title>. In: <source>Opuscula Atheniensa. Annual of the Swedish Institute at Athens. Stockholm</source> <year>1997/98</year>. Bd. <volume>22</volume> <other>- 23</other> S. 7 - <fpage>52</fpage>.<raw>Billot, M.-F.: Sanctuaire et cultes d’Athéna à Argos. In: Opuscula Atheniensa. Annual of the Swedish Institute at Athens. Stockholm 1997/98. Bd. 22 - 23. S. 7 - 52.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bursian</surname>, <given-names>Conrad</given-names></author>: <title>Geographie von Grie chenland. Gerstenbergverlag</title>. <other>Hildesheim 1977. Ersterscheinung</other> <publisher>Verlag B. G. Teubner</publisher> <other>Leipzig</other> <year>1868</year>. Bd. <volume>II</volume>. S. <fpage>39</fpage> - 49<raw>Bursian, Conrad: Geographie von Grie chenland. Gerstenbergverlag. Hildesheim 1977. Ersterscheinung: Verlag B. G. Teubner. Leipzig 1868. Bd. II. S. 39 - 49.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Cauer</surname>, <given-names>F</given-names></author>.: <author><surname>Argolis</surname></author>. In: <editor>Paulys Realencyclopädie der classischen Altertumswissenschaft. Hg.: Wissowa, Georg. J. B. Metzlerscher Verlag</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other> <year>1896</year>. Bd. <volume>II</volume>. S. <fpage>728</fpage> - <other>743</other>.<raw>Cauer, F.: Argolis. In: Paulys Realencyclopädie der classischen Altertumswissenschaft. Hg.: Wissowa, Georg. J. B. Metzlerscher Verlag. Stuttgart 1896. Bd. II. S. 728 - 743.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hägg</surname>, <given-names>Robin</given-names></author>: <title>Zur Stadtwerdeung des dorischen Argos</title>. In: <source>Palast und</source> <title>Hütte. Beiträge zum Bauen und Wohnen im Altertum von Archäologen, Vor- und Frühgeschichtlern. Tagungsbeiträge eines Symposions der Alexander von Humboldt-Stiftung Bonn-Bad Godesberg veranstaltet vom</title> <other>25</other>. - 30 <other>November 1979</other> in <editor>Berlin. Hg.: Papenfuss, Dietrich</editor> <other>Strocka</other>, <publisher>Volker Michael. Verlag Philipp von Zabern</publisher> <other>Mainz am Rhein</other> <year>1982</year>. S. <fpage>297</fpage> - <other>307</other>.<raw>Hägg, Robin: Zur Stadtwerdeung des dorischen Argos. In: Palast und Hütte. Beiträge zum Bauen und Wohnen im Altertum von Archäologen, Vor- und Frühgeschichtlern. Tagungsbeiträge eines Symposions der Alexander von Humboldt-Stiftung Bonn-Bad Godesberg veranstaltet vom 25. - 30. November 1979 in Berlin. Hg.: Papenfuss, Dietrich; Strocka, Volker Michael. Verlag Philipp von Zabern. Mainz am Rhein 1982. S. 297 - 307.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hall</surname>, <given-names>J</given-names></author>.: <title>Alternative responses within polis formation: Argos, Mykenai and Tiryns</title>. In: <source>Urbanization in</source> <title>the mediterranean in the 9 th to the 6</title> th <editor>centuries B. C. Hg.: Andersen, Helle Damgaard; Horsnaes, Helle W.; Houby-Nielsen, Sanne; Rathje, Annette</editor> <publisher>Museum Tusculanum press; University of Copenhagen</publisher> <other>Copenhagen</other> <year>1997</year>. S. <fpage>89</fpage> - 109<raw>Hall, J.: Alternative responses within polis formation: Argos, Mykenai and Tiryns. In: Urbanization in the mediterranean in the 9 th to the 6 th centuries B. C. Hg.: Andersen, Helle Damgaard; Horsnaes, Helle W.; Houby-Nielsen, Sanne; Rathje, Annette. Museum Tusculanum press; University of Copenhagen. Copenhagen 1997. S. 89 - 109.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kelly</surname>, <given-names>Thomas</given-names></author>: <title>A History of Argos</title> to 500 B. C. In <source>Minnesota Monographs in the</source> <publisher>Humanities. University of Minnesota Press</publisher> <other>Minneapolis</other> <year>1976</year>. Vol. <volume>9</volume>.<raw>Kelly, Thomas: A History of Argos to 500 B. C. In: Minnesota Monographs in the Humanities. University of Minnesota Press. Minneapolis 1976. Vol. 9.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lauffer</surname>, <given-names>Siegfried</given-names></author> (<title>Hg): Griechenland. Lexikon der historischen Stätten. Von den Anfängen bis zur Gegenwart</title>. C. H <title>Beck’sche Verlagsbuchhandlung</title>. <other>München</other> <year>1989</year>. S. <fpage>128</fpage> - <other>131</other>.<raw>Lauffer, Siegfried (Hg): Griechenland. Lexikon der historischen Stätten. Von den Anfängen bis zur Gegenwart. C. H. Beck’sche Verlagsbuchhandlung. München 1989. S. 128 - 131.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Oppermann</surname>, <given-names>Siemer</given-names></author>: <title>Peloponnes / Siemer Oppermann. Artemis und Winkler</title>. <other>München</other> <year>1993</year>. S. <fpage>94</fpage> - <other>104</other>.<raw>Oppermann, Siemer: Peloponnes / Siemer Oppermann. Artemis und Winkler. München 1993. S. 94 - 104.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Pötscher</surname>, <given-names>Walter</given-names></author>: <title>Das Hera - Fest im Heraion von Argos (Hdt. 1, 31 und Eur. El</title>. <volume>169ff</volume>). In: <source>Acta Antiqua Academiae Scienitarum Hungariae. Budapest 1996/97</source> Bd. <volume>37</volume>. S. <fpage>25</fpage> - 36<raw>Pötscher, Walter: Das Hera - Fest im Heraion von Argos (Hdt. 1, 31 und Eur. El. 169ff). In: Acta Antiqua Academiae Scienitarum Hungariae. Budapest 1996/97. Bd. 37. S. 25 - 36.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Speich</surname>, <given-names>Richard</given-names></author>: <title>Peloponnes: Kunst- und Reiseführer mit Landeskunde</title> / Richard Speich <issue>2</issue>. und erw. Aufl. Kohlhammer <other>Stuttgart, Berlin, Köln</other> <year>1989</year>. S. <fpage>131</fpage> - <other>142</other>.<raw>Speich, Richard: Peloponnes: Kunst- und Reiseführer mit Landeskunde / Richard Speich. 2. und erw. Aufl. Kohlhammer. Stuttgart, Berlin, Köln 1989. S. 131 - 142.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Tausend</surname>, <given-names>Klaus</given-names></author>: <title>Pheidon von Argos und das argolische Aigina</title>. In: <source>Grazer Beiträge. Graz/Salzburg</source> <year>1995</year>. Bd. <volume>21</volume>. S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <issue>5</issue>.<raw>Tausend, Klaus: Pheidon von Argos und das argolische Aigina. In: Grazer Beiträge. Graz/Salzburg 1995. Bd. 21. S. 1 - 5.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Tomlinson</surname>, <given-names>Richard</given-names></author> <author><surname>Allen</surname></author>: <title>Argos and the Argolid. From the End of the Bronze Age to the Roman Occupation. Routledge</title>. <other>London</other> <year>1972</year>.<raw>Tomlinson, Richard Allen: Argos and the Argolid. From the End of the Bronze Age to the Roman Occupation. Routledge. London 1972.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Touchais</surname>, <given-names>Gilles</given-names></author>: <title>Argos a l’age du bronze: état present des recherches</title>. In: <source>Attiememorie del</source> <title>secondo congreso internazionale di micenologia</title>. Roma - Napoli, 14 -20 ottobre <year>1991</year>. Hg.: Miro <editor>Ernesto De; Godart, Louis; Sacconi, Anna</editor> Vol. <volume>I</volume>: <source>Filologia</source>; Vol. <volume>II</volume>: <publisher>Storia</publisher>; Vol. III <title>Archeologia. GEI (Gruppo editoriale internazionale</title>). <other>Roma</other> <year>1996</year>. S. <fpage>1319</fpage> - <other>1326</other>.<raw>Touchais, Gilles: Argos a l’age du bronze: état present des recherches. In: Attiememorie del secondo congreso internazionale di micenologia. Roma - Napoli, 14 -20 ottobre 1991. Hg.: Miro, Ernesto De; Godart, Louis; Sacconi, Anna. Vol. I: Filologia; Vol. II: Storia; Vol. III: Archeologia. GEI (Gruppo editoriale internazionale). Roma 1996. S. 1319 - 1326.</raw></sequence>