<sequence><author><surname>Stoker</surname>, <given-names>Bram, Dracula</given-names></author> <other>Oxford</other>: <publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher> <year>1983</year><raw>Stoker, Bram, Dracula. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1983</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bentley</surname>, <given-names>C.F</given-names></author>., ”<title>The monster in the bedroom: Sexual Symbolism in Bram Stoker’s Dracula</title>”. In: <source>Literature and psychology</source> <volume>22</volume> (<year>1972</year>), S. <fpage>27</fpage> - <issue>34</issue><raw>Bentley, C.F., ”The monster in the bedroom: Sexual Symbolism in Bram Stoker’s Dracula”. In: Literature and psychology, 22 (1972), S. 27 - 34</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Foldy</surname>, <given-names>Michael S.</given-names></author> “<title>The cultural climate of the Trials: Heterosexism and Homophobia as Historical Constructs</title>”. In: <source>The Trials of Oscar Wilde</source> <other>New Haven, Conn.: Yale UP</other> <year>1997</year><raw>Foldy, Michael S., “The cultural climate of the Trials: Heterosexism and Homophobia as Historical Constructs”. In: The Trials of Oscar Wilde. New Haven, Conn.: Yale UP, 1997</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Harris</surname>, <given-names>Marvin</given-names></author>, „<title>Mann mit Mann</title>“. In: <source>Menschen: Wie</source> <title>wir wurden, was wir sind</title>. <other>München</other>: <publisher>dtv</publisher>, <year>1997</year><raw>Harris, Marvin, „Mann mit Mann“. In: Menschen: Wie wir wurden, was wir sind. München: dtv, 1997</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Pfister</surname>, <given-names>Schulte-Middelich</given-names></author> (Hgb.), „The <given-names>Other</given-names> <author><surname>Victorians</surname></author>. <title>Viktorianismus und sexuelle Revolution</title>“. In: <source>Die Nineties</source> <title>das englische Fin de siècle zwischen Dekadenz und Sozialkritik</title>. <other>München</other>: <publisher>Fink/utb</publisher>, <year>1983</year><raw>Pfister, Schulte-Middelich (Hgb.), „The Other Victorians. Viktorianismus und sexuelle Revolution“. In: Die Nineties: das englische Fin de siècle zwischen Dekadenz und Sozialkritik. München: Fink/utb, 1983</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Steele</surname>, <given-names>Valerie, Fashion</given-names></author> <title>and Eroticism: Ideals of feminine beauty from the Victorian Era to the Jazz Age</title>. <other>Oxford</other>: <publisher>Oxford UP</publisher> <year>1985</year><raw>Steele, Valerie, Fashion and Eroticism: Ideals of feminine beauty from the Victorian Era to the Jazz Age. Oxford: Oxford UP, 1985</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stevenson</surname>, <given-names>John</given-names></author> <author><surname>Allen</surname></author> “, <title>A vampire in the mirror</title>”. In: <source>Publications of the modern language association of America</source> <volume>103:2</volume> (<year>1988</year>), S. <fpage>139</fpage> - <other>149</other><raw>Stevenson, John Allen, “ A vampire in the mirror”. In: Publications of the modern language association of America, 103:2 (1988), S. 139 - 149</raw></sequence>