<sequence><author><surname>BENGTSON</surname>, <given-names>Herrmann</given-names></author>: <title>Die Flavier: Vespasian, Titus, Domitian. Geschichte eines römischen Kaiserhauses</title>, <other>München</other> <year>1979</year><raw>BENGTSON, Herrmann: Die Flavier: Vespasian, Titus, Domitian. Geschichte eines römischen Kaiserhauses, München 1979</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>COLEMAN</surname>, <given-names>K. M.</given-names></author> <title>The Emperor Domitian and Literature</title>, in: <editor>HAASE, Wolfgang</editor> (Hg.): <source>ANRW II</source> <volume>32.5</volume>, <other>Berlin</other> / <other>New York</other> <year>1986</year>, <volume>3087</volume> – <fpage>3115</fpage><raw>COLEMAN, K. M.: The Emperor Domitian and Literature, in: HAASE, Wolfgang (Hg.): ANRW II 32.5, Berlin / New York 1986, 3087 – 3115</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GARTHWAITE</surname>, <given-names>John</given-names></author>: <title>Putting a Price on Praise. Martial’s Debate with Domitian</title> <source>in Book</source> <volume>5</volume>, in <editor>GREWING, Farouk</editor> (Hg.): <source>Toto notus in orbe. Perspektiven der Martial – Interpretation</source> <other>Stuttgart</other> <year>1998</year> (=<other>Palingenesia 65)</other><raw>GARTHWAITE, John: Putting a Price on Praise. Martial’s Debate with Domitian in Book 5, in GREWING, Farouk (Hg.): Toto notus in orbe. Perspektiven der Martial – Interpretation, Stuttgart 1998 (=Palingenesia 65)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>HOFMANN</surname>, <given-names>Walter</given-names></author>: <title>Martial und Domitian</title>, <source>Philologus</source> <volume>127</volume> (<year>1983</year>), <fpage>238</fpage> – <issue>246</issue><raw>HOFMANN, Walter: Martial und Domitian, Philologus 127 (1983), 238 – 246</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>HOWELL</surname>, <given-names>Peter</given-names></author>: <title>Martial</title> <author><surname>Epigrams</surname> <given-names>V</given-names></author> <title>Edited with an Introduction, Translation</title> and Commentary, Warminster <year>1995</year><raw>HOWELL, Peter: Martial. Epigrams V, Edited with an Introduction, Translation and Commentary, Warminster 1995</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>M</surname>. <given-names>Val</given-names></author>. <title>MARTIALIS, Epigrammata, Recognovit brevique adnotatione critica instruxit</title> W. M. Lindsay, Editio altera <other>Oxford</other> <year>1929</year> (= <source>Scriptorum Classicorum Bibliotheca Oxoniensis)</source><raw>M. Val. MARTIALIS, Epigrammata, Recognovit brevique adnotatione critica instruxit W. M. Lindsay, Editio altera, Oxford 1929 (= Scriptorum Classicorum Bibliotheca Oxoniensis)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>SZELEST</surname>, <given-names>Hanna</given-names></author>: <title>Martial – eigentlicher Schöpfer und hervorragendster Vertreter des römischen Epigramms</title>, in: <editor>HAASE, Wolfgang</editor> (Hg.): <source>ANRW II</source> <volume>32.4</volume>, <other>Berlin</other> – New <other>York</other> <year>1986</year>, <other>2563</other> - <fpage>2623</fpage><raw>SZELEST, Hanna: Martial – eigentlicher Schöpfer und hervorragendster Vertreter des römischen Epigramms, in: HAASE, Wolfgang (Hg.): ANRW II 32.4, Berlin – New York 1986, 2563 - 2623</raw></sequence>