<sequence><author><surname>Andreae</surname>, <given-names>B</given-names></author> <year>1983</year>. <title>Agrargeographie. Strukturzonen und Betriebsformen in der Weltlandwirtschaft</title>. <other>Berlin; New York</other> <publisher>Walter de Gruyter Verlag</publisher> <other>Berlin</other>.<raw>Andreae, B. 1983. Agrargeographie. Strukturzonen und Betriebsformen in der Weltlandwirtschaft. Berlin; New York. Walter de Gruyter Verlag. Berlin.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Andeae</surname>, <given-names>B</given-names></author> <year>1985</year>. <title>Allgemeine Agrargeographie</title>. <other>Berlin. Walter</other> <publisher>de Gruyter Verlag</publisher><raw>Andeae, B. 1985. Allgemeine Agrargeographie. Berlin. Walter de Gruyter Verlag</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Benneh</surname>, <given-names>G</given-names></author> <year>1972</year>. <title>The Response of Farmers in Northern Ghana and the Introduction of mixed farming: A case study</title>. <source>In Geografiska Annaler. Stockkolm</source> <volume>54</volume>, <issue>2</issue>: S. <fpage>95</fpage> - <lpage>103</lpage><raw>Benneh, G. 1972. The Response of Farmers in Northern Ghana and the Introduction of mixed farming: A case study. In Geografiska Annaler. Stockkolm. 54, 2: S. 95-103</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fratkin</surname>, <given-names>E</given-names></author>., <author><surname>Galvin</surname>, <given-names>K</given-names></author> <year>1994</year>. <title>African Pastoralist Systems. An Integrated Approach</title>. Boulder – <other>Colorado</other>. <publisher>Lynne Rienner Publishers</publisher><raw>Fratkin, E., Galvin, K. 1994. African Pastoralist Systems. An Integrated Approach. Boulder – Colorado. Lynne Rienner Publishers</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Herzog</surname></author> <year>1963</year>. <title>Sesshaftwerden von Nomaden. Geschichte gegenwärtiger Stand eines wirtschaftlichen sowie sozialen Prozesses und möglichkeiten der sinnvollen technischen Nutzung</title>. <other>Köln</other>. <publisher>Westdeutscher Verlag</publisher><raw>Herzog 1963. Sesshaftwerden von Nomaden. Geschichte gegenwärtiger Stand eines wirtschaftlichen sowie sozialen Prozesses und möglichkeiten der sinnvollen technischen Nutzung. Köln. Westdeutscher Verlag</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Leser</surname>  <given-names>H</given-names></author> <year>1995</year>: <title>Diercke Wörterbuch der allgemeinen Geographie</title>. Bd.1, <volume>2</volume>. <other>München</other><raw>Leser , H. 1995: Diercke Wörterbuch der allgemeinen Geographie. Bd.1, 2. München</raw></sequence><sequence><source>Microsoft Encarta</source> <year>2001</year><raw>Microsoft Encarta 2001</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Nicolaisen</surname>, <given-names>J</given-names></author>., <author><surname>Nicolaisen</surname>, <given-names>I</given-names></author> <year>1997</year>. <title>The pastoral Tuareg. Ecology, Culture, and Society</title>. <source>Kopenhagen. Rhodos International Science</source> <publisher>and Art Publishers</publisher><raw>Nicolaisen, J., Nicolaisen, I. 1997. The pastoral Tuareg. Ecology, Culture, and Society. Kopenhagen. Rhodos International Science and Art Publishers</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Prasse</surname>, <given-names>K. –G.1995</given-names></author> <author><surname>The</surname></author> <title>Tuaregs. The Blue People. Odense – Dänemark</title>. <publisher>Museum Transculanum Press</publisher><raw>Prasse, K. –G.1995. The Tuaregs. The Blue People. Odense – Dänemark. Museum Transculanum Press</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Scholz</surname>, <given-names>F</given-names></author> <year>1992</year>: <title>Nomadismus – Bibliographie</title>. <other>Berlin. Das arabische Buch</other><raw>Scholz, F. 1992: Nomadismus – Bibliographie. Berlin. Das arabische Buch</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Tonah</surname>, <given-names>S</given-names></author> <year>1993</year>. <title>The Development of Agropastoral Households in Northern Ghana: Policy Analysis, Project Appraisal and Future Perspectives</title>. <publisher>Saarbrücken. breitenbach Publishers</publisher><raw>Tonah, S. 1993. The Development of Agropastoral Households in Northern Ghana: Policy Analysis, Project Appraisal and Future Perspectives. Saarbrücken. breitenbach Publishers</raw></sequence>