<sequence><author><surname>Aitchison</surname>, <given-names>Jean</given-names></author>. <title>The Articulate Mammal: An Introduction to Psycholingiustics</title>. <issue>3</issue>. Aufl. <other>London</other>: <publisher>Routledge</publisher>, <year>1989</year>.<raw>Aitchison, Jean. The Articulate Mammal: An Introduction to Psycholingiustics. 3. Aufl. London: Routledge, 1989.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Aitchison</surname>, <given-names>Jean</given-names></author>. <title>Words in the Mind: An Introduction to the Mental Lexicon</title>. <issue>2</issue>. Aufl. <other>Oxford</other>: <publisher>Blackwell</publisher>, <year>1994</year>.<raw>Aitchison, Jean. Words in the Mind: An Introduction to the Mental Lexicon. 2. Aufl. Oxford: Blackwell, 1994.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Feldman</surname>, <given-names>J. A</given-names></author> und <author><given-names>D. H</given-names></author> <source>Ballard. „Connectionist Models and their Properties“</source><raw>Feldman, J. A. und D. H. Ballard. „Connectionist Models and their Properties“.</raw></sequence><sequence><source>Cognitive Science</source> <volume>6</volume> (<year>1982</year>): <fpage>205</fpage> - <lpage>254</lpage>. Zit. in <editor>Scott E. Lively, David B. Pisoni</editor> und <author><surname>Stephen D</surname></author> <title>Goldinger. „Spoken Word Recognition: Research and Theory</title>“. <source>Handbook of Psycholingiustics</source> Hg. <source>Morton Ann Gernsbacher</source> <other>London</other>: <publisher>Academic Press</publisher> <year>1994</year>. 265-301.<raw>Cognitive Science 6 (1982): 205-254. Zit. in Scott E. Lively, David B. Pisoni und Stephen D. Goldinger. „Spoken Word Recognition: Research and Theory“. Handbook of Psycholingiustics. Hg. Morton Ann Gernsbacher. London: Academic Press, 1994. 265-301.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fodor</surname>, <given-names>J. A., T. G</given-names></author> <author><surname>Bever</surname> und <given-names>M. F</given-names></author> <author><surname>Garrett</surname></author>. <title>The Psychology of Language</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>Mc Graw</publisher> <other>Hill</other>, <year>1974</year>. <title>Zit. in Jean Aitchison. The Articulate Mammal: An Introduction to Psycholinguistics</title>. <issue>3</issue>. Aufl. <other>London</other>: <publisher>Routledge</publisher>, <year>1989</year>.<raw>Fodor, J. A., T. G. Bever und M. F. Garrett. The Psychology of Language. New York: Mc Graw Hill, 1974. Zit. in Jean Aitchison. The Articulate Mammal: An Introduction to Psycholinguistics. 3. Aufl. London: Routledge, 1989.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>James</surname>, <given-names>William. The</given-names></author> <title>Principles of Psychology</title>. <issue>1</issue>. Bd. Cambridge <title>Harvard UP</title>, <year>1981</year>. <title>Zit. in Jean Aitchison. Words in the Mind: An Introduction to the Mental Lexicon</title>. <issue>2</issue>. Aufl. <other>Oxford</other>: <publisher>Blackwell</publisher>, <year>1994</year>.<raw>James, William. The Principles of Psychology. 1. Bd. Cambridge: Harvard UP, 1981. Zit. in Jean Aitchison. Words in the Mind: An Introduction to the Mental Lexicon. 2. Aufl. Oxford: Blackwell, 1994.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Schwarz</surname>, <given-names>Monika</given-names></author>. <title>Einführung in die kognitive Linguistik</title>. <issue>2</issue>. Aufl. <other>Tübingen</other>: <publisher>Francke</publisher>, <year>1996</year>.<raw>Schwarz, Monika. Einführung in die kognitive Linguistik. 2. Aufl. Tübingen: Francke, 1996.</raw></sequence>