<sequence><author><surname>CHING</surname>, <given-names>Leo</given-names></author>: <title>Imaginings in the Empires of the Sun: Japanese Mass Culture in Asia</title>, in: <source>Boundary</source> <volume>2</volume> <fpage>21</fpage> - <lpage>1</lpage>, <other>Durham NC</other> <publisher>Duke University Press</publisher> <year>1994</year>.<raw>CHING, Leo: Imaginings in the Empires of the Sun: Japanese Mass Culture in Asia, in: Boundary 2 21:1, Durham NC: Duke University Press, 1994.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>CHUA</surname>, <given-names>Beng</given-names></author> <title>Huat: Life is not complete without shopping – Consumption Culture in Singapore</title>, <other>Singapore</other>: <publisher>Singapore University Press</publisher> <year>2003</year>.<raw>CHUA, Beng Huat: Life is not complete without shopping – Consumption Culture in Singapore, Singapore: Singapore University Press, 2003.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>COUPLAND</surname>, <given-names>Douglas</given-names></author>: <title>Generation X'd</title>, in: <editor>Details Magazine</editor> <other>Juni</other> <year>1995</year>.<raw>COUPLAND, Douglas: Generation X'd, in: Details Magazine, Juni 1995.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>EWING</surname>, <given-names>Michael T. &</given-names></author> <author><surname>CARUANA</surname>, <given-names>Albert</given-names></author>: <title>Communicating with the Cohort: Exploring Generation X ASIA’S Attitudes Towards Advertising</title>, in: <editor>Schütte, Helmut</editor> & <author><surname>Ciarlante</surname>, <given-names>Deanna</given-names></author>: <title>Consumer Behaviour in Asia</title>, <other>New York</other> <publisher>Haworth Press</publisher> <year>1999</year>.<raw>EWING, Michael T. & CARUANA, Albert: Communicating with the Cohort: Exploring Generation X ASIA’S Attitudes Towards Advertising, in: Schütte, Helmut & Ciarlante, Deanna: Consumer Behaviour in Asia, New York: Haworth Press, 1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>FINKELSTEIN</surname>, <given-names>Joanne</given-names></author>: <title>The Anomic World of the High Consumer: Fashion and Cultural Formation</title>, in: <editor>Chua, Beng Huat</editor> (Hg.): <source>Consumption in Asia</source> – <title>Lifestyles and Identities, The New Rich in Asia series</title>, <other>London, New York</other> <publisher>Routledge</publisher>, <year>2000</year>.<raw>FINKELSTEIN, Joanne: The Anomic World of the High Consumer: Fashion and Cultural Formation, in: Chua, Beng Huat (Hg.): Consumption in Asia – Lifestyles and Identities, The New Rich in Asia series, London, New York: Routledge, 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GERKE</surname>, <given-names>Solvay</given-names></author>: <title>Global Lifestyles und Local conditions. The New Indonesian Middle Class, South East Asian Studies</title> <source>Working Paper No.1</source> <other>Bonn</other>: <publisher>Universität</publisher> <other>Bonn</other>, <year>1999</year>.<raw>GERKE, Solvay: Global Lifestyles und Local conditions. The New Indonesian Middle Class, South East Asian Studies Working Paper No.1, Bonn: Universität Bonn, 1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>MCGRAY</surname>, <given-names>Douglas</given-names></author>: <title>Japan ’s Gross National Cool</title>, in: <editor>Foreign Policy</editor> <other>June/July</other> <year>2002</year>.<raw>MCGRAY, Douglas: Japan ’s Gross National Cool, in: Foreign Policy, June/July 2002.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>NATHAN</surname>, <given-names>J.M</given-names></author>.: <author><surname>Reframing Modernity</surname></author> – <title>The Challenge of Remaking Singapore</title>, in: <editor>DaCunha, Derek</editor> (Hg.): <source>Singapore in the New Millennium. Challenges facing the City-state</source> <other>Singapore</other>: <year>2002</year>.<raw>NATHAN, J.M.: Reframing Modernity – The Challenge of Remaking Singapore, in: DaCunha, Derek (Hg.): Singapore in the New Millennium. Challenges facing the City-state, Singapore: 2002.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>YASUE</surname>, <given-names>Mariko</given-names></author> & <author><surname>GU</surname>, <given-names>Xiang Wen</given-names></author> <title>Asian Youth and Implications for Marketing Strategies. Changes and Differences in Consumption Attitudes and Lifestyle Values</title>, in: <author><surname>Leong</surname>, <given-names>SM</given-names></author>; <author><surname>Ang</surname>, <given-names>SH</given-names></author>; <author><surname>Tan</surname>, <given-names>CT</given-names></author>: <title>Marketing in the New Asia</title>, <other>Singapore</other>: <publisher>McGraw Hill</publisher> <year>2001</year>.<raw>YASUE, Mariko & GU, Xiang Wen: Asian Youth and Implications for Marketing Strategies. Changes and Differences in Consumption Attitudes and Lifestyle Values, in: Leong, SM; Ang, SH; Tan, CT: Marketing in the New Asia, Singapore: McGraw Hill, 2001.</raw></sequence>