<sequence><author><surname>Acosta</surname>, <given-names>José</given-names></author> <title>de. Natural and Moral History of the Indies</title>. <other>Durham</other>, <year>2002</year>.<raw>Acosta, José de. Natural and Moral History of the Indies. Durham, 2002.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Frenkel</surname>, <given-names>Stephan. Jungle</given-names></author> <title>Stories: North American Representations of Tropical Panama</title>. In: <source>Geographical Review</source> Vol. <volume>86</volume>, No. <issue>3</issue>, Latin American Geography <year>1996</year>.<raw>Frenkel, Stephan. Jungle Stories: North American Representations of Tropical Panama. In: Geographical Review, Vol. 86, No. 3, Latin American Geography, 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Greene</surname>, <given-names>Julie</given-names></author>. <title>The Canal Builders. Making America's empire at the Panama Canal</title>. <other>New York</other> <year>2009</year><raw>Greene, Julie. The Canal Builders. Making America's empire at the Panama Canal. New York, 2009</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Keller, Ullrich</surname></author> <title>The Building of the Panama Canal in Historic Photographs</title>. <other>New York</other> <year>1983</year>.<raw>Keller, Ullrich. The Building of the Panama Canal in Historic Photographs. New York, 1983.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>McCullough</surname>, <given-names>David. Sie</given-names></author> <title>Teilten die Erde. Abenteuer und Geschichte der letzten großen Pioniertat - der Erbauung des Panama-Kanals</title>. <other>München</other>, <year>1978</year>.<raw>McCullough, David. Sie Teilten die Erde. Abenteuer und Geschichte der letzten großen Pioniertat - der Erbauung des Panama-Kanals. München, 1978.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Merwin</surname>, <given-names>G. B</given-names></author> <title>Three Years in Chile</title>. <other>London</other>, <year>1966</year>.<raw>Merwin, G. B. Three Years in Chile. London, 1966.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Missal</surname>, <given-names>Alexander</given-names></author>. <title>Seaway to the Future. American Social Visions and the Construction of the Panama Canal</title>. <other>Madison</other>, <year>2008</year>.<raw>Missal, Alexander. Seaway to the Future. American Social Visions and the Construction of the Panama Canal. Madison, 2008.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Putnam</surname>, <given-names>G. P</given-names></author> <title>The Southland of North America: Rambles and Observations in Central America during the Year 1912</title>. <other>New York</other> <year>1913</year>.<raw>Putnam, G. P. The Southland of North America: Rambles and Observations in Central America during the Year 1912. New York, 1913.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Schild</surname>, <given-names>Thomas</given-names></author>. <title>Der Kampf um den Panamakanal</title>. In: <source>Die Zeit, 51/1999</source><raw>Schild, Thomas. Der Kampf um den Panamakanal. In: Die Zeit, 51/1999.</raw></sequence><sequence><publisher>Internetquellen</publisher><raw>Internetquellen</raw></sequence><sequence>URL: <url>http://www.20min.ch/interaktiv/kanaele/film.html Format: HTML</url> [<other>Letzter Zugriff: 19.03.2012]</other><raw>URL: http://www.20min.ch/interaktiv/kanaele/film.html Format: HTML [Letzter Zugriff: 19.03.2012]</raw></sequence><sequence>URL: <url>http://www.info-panama.com/panamakanal.html Format: HTML</url> [<other>Letzter Zugriff: 19.03.2012]</other><raw>URL: http://www.info-panama.com/panamakanal.html Format: HTML [Letzter Zugriff: 19.03.2012]</raw></sequence>