<sequence><title>Beowulf and its Analogues. Translated by G. N. Garmonsway and Jaqueline Simpson</title>, hrsg. von <editor>George Norman Garmonsway</editor> und <editor>Jaqueline Simpson</editor> (<other>London</other> <year>1969</year>)<raw>Beowulf and its Analogues. Translated by G. N. Garmonsway and Jaqueline Simpson, hrsg. von George Norman Garmonsway und Jaqueline Simpson (London 1969)</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Beowulf and the Fight at Finnsburg</title>, hrsg. von <editor>Fr. Klaeber</editor> (<other>Boston</other> <year>1950</year>)<raw>Beowulf and the Fight at Finnsburg, hrsg. von Fr. Klaeber (Boston 1950)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Beowulf</surname>. <given-names>A</given-names></author> <title>Student edition</title>, hrsg. von <editor>G. Jack</editor> (Oxford, <year>1994</year>)<raw>Beowulf. A Student edition, hrsg. von G. Jack (Oxford, 1994)</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Beowulf und die kleineren Denkmäler der altenglischen Heldensage Waldere und Finnsburg</title>. <volume>1</volume>. <source>Teil. Text, Übersetzung, Namensverzeichnis und Stammtafeln</source> hrsg. von <editor>Gerhard Nickel</editor> (<other>Heidelberg</other> <year>1976</year>)<raw>Beowulf und die kleineren Denkmäler der altenglischen Heldensage Waldere und Finnsburg. 1. Teil. Text, Übersetzung, Namensverzeichnis und Stammtafeln, hrsg. von Gerhard Nickel (Heidelberg 1976)</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Die Bibel. Nach der Übersetzung Martin Luthers</title>. Mit Apokryphen, hrsg. von <editor>der Evangelischen Kirche Deutschlands</editor> (<other>Stuttgart</other> <year>1984</year>)<raw>Die Bibel. Nach der Übersetzung Martin Luthers. Mit Apokryphen, hrsg. von der Evangelischen Kirche Deutschlands (Stuttgart 1984)</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Die Edda. Götterdichtung, Spruchweisheit und Heldengesänge der Germanen</title>, <other>übers. von Felix Genzmer (Düsseldorf</other> <year>1981</year>)<raw>Die Edda. Götterdichtung, Spruchweisheit und Heldengesänge der Germanen, übers. von Felix Genzmer (Düsseldorf 1981)</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Grettis saga. Die Saga von Grettir dem Starken, hrsg. und übers</title>. <other>von Hubert Seelow (München</other> <year>1998</year>)<raw>Grettis saga. Die Saga von Grettir dem Starken, hrsg. und übers. von Hubert Seelow (München 1998)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Andersson</surname>, <given-names>Theodore M.</given-names></author> “<title>Sources and Analogues</title>”, in: <editor>A Beowulf Handbook, Hrsg. Bjork, Robert E</editor> and John D. Niles (Lincoln <year>1997</year>), S. <fpage>125</fpage> - <lpage>148</lpage><raw>Andersson, Theodore M., “Sources and Analogues”, in: A Beowulf Handbook, Hrsg. Bjork, Robert E. and John D. Niles (Lincoln 1997), S. 125-148</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Benson</surname>, <given-names>Larry D.</given-names></author> „<title>The Originality of Beowulf”, in: Contradictions: From Beowulf to Chaucer</title>. <source>Selected Studies</source> of Larry D. Benson, hrsg. von <editor>Theodore M. Andersson</editor> und <editor>Stephen A. Barney</editor> (<other>Aldershot 1995)</other> <fpage>S</fpage> - <lpage>32</fpage> - <lpage>69</lpage><raw>Benson, Larry D., „The Originality of Beowulf”, in: Contradictions: From Beowulf to Chaucer. Selected Studies of Larry D. Benson, hrsg. von Theodore M. Andersson und Stephen A. Barney (Aldershot 1995), S.32-69</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Benson</surname>, <given-names>Larry D.</given-names></author> „<title>The Pagan Colouring of Beowulf”, in: Contradictions: From Beowulf to Chaucer</title>. <source>Selected Studies</source> of Larry D. Benson, hrsg. von <editor>Theodore M. Andersson</editor> und <editor>Stephen A. Barney</editor> (Aldershot <year>1995</year>), S. <fpage>1</fpage> - <lpage>31</lpage><raw>Benson, Larry D., „The Pagan Colouring of Beowulf”, in: Contradictions: From Beowulf to Chaucer. Selected Studies of Larry D. Benson, hrsg. von Theodore M. Andersson und Stephen A. Barney (Aldershot 1995), S. 1-31</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Chambers</surname>, <given-names>Raymond</given-names></author> <title>Wilson, Beowulf. An Introduction</title> (<year>Cambridge1959</year>)<raw>Chambers, Raymond Wilson, Beowulf. An Introduction (Cambridge1959)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Earl</surname>, <given-names>James W.</given-names></author> Thinking about <editor>Beowulf</editor> (<other>Stanford</other> <year>1994</year>)<raw>Earl, James W., Thinking about Beowulf (Stanford 1994)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fjalldal</surname>, <given-names>Magnus</given-names></author>, <title>The Long Arm of Coincidence. The Frustrated Connection between Beowulf and Grettis saga</title> (<other>Toronto</other> <year>1998</year>)<raw>Fjalldal, Magnus, The Long Arm of Coincidence. The Frustrated Connection between Beowulf and Grettis saga (Toronto 1998)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Kaske</surname>, <given-names>R.E</given-names></author>., “<title>Beowulf and the Book of Enoch”, Speculum</title>. <source>A Journal of Mediaeval Studies</source> <volume>46</volume> (<year>1971</year>), <fpage>421</fpage> - <lpage>431</lpage><raw>Kaske, R.E., “Beowulf and the Book of Enoch”, Speculum. A Journal of Mediaeval Studies 46 (1971), 421-431</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lionarons</surname>, <given-names>Joyce Tally</given-names></author>  <title>The Medieval Dragon: the Nature of the Beast in Germanic Literature</title> (<other>Middlesex</other> <year>1998</year>)<raw>Lionarons, Joyce Tally , The Medieval Dragon: the Nature of the Beast in Germanic Literature (Middlesex 1998)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Leake</surname>, <given-names>Jane A.</given-names></author> <title>The Geats of Beowulf</title> (<other>London</other> <year>1967</year>)<raw>Leake, Jane A., The Geats of Beowulf (London 1967)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Niles</surname>, <given-names>John D.</given-names></author> <title>Beowulf. The Poem and Its Tradition</title> (<other>London</other> <year>1983</year>)<raw>Niles, John D., Beowulf. The Poem and Its Tradition (London 1983)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Niles</surname>, <given-names>John D.</given-names></author> “<title>Myth and History</title>”, in: <source>A Beowulf Handbook</source> hrsg. von <editor>Robert E. Bjork</editor> und <editor>John D. Niles</editor> (<year>Lincoln1997</year>), S. <fpage>211</fpage> - <lpage>232</lpage><raw>Niles, John D., “Myth and History”, in: A Beowulf Handbook, hrsg. von Robert E. Bjork und John D. Niles (Lincoln1997), S. 211-232</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Newton</surname>, <given-names>Sam</given-names></author>, <title>The Origins of Beowulf and the Pre-Viking Kingdom of East Anglia</title> (<other>Cambridge</other> <year>1993</year>)<raw>Newton, Sam, The Origins of Beowulf and the Pre-Viking Kingdom of East Anglia (Cambridge 1993)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Ogilvy</surname>, <given-names>J.D.A</given-names></author>. und <author><surname>Baker</surname>, <given-names>Donald C.</given-names></author> <title>Reading Beowulf. An Introduction to the Poem, Its Background, and its Style</title> (<other>Oklahoma</other> <year>1983</year>)<raw>Ogilvy, J.D.A. und Baker, Donald C., Reading Beowulf. An Introduction to the Poem, Its Background, and its Style (Oklahoma 1983)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Orchard, Andy</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></author> <title>Critical Companion to Beowulf</title> (<other>Cambridge 2003)</other><raw>Orchard, Andy, A Critical Companion to Beowulf (Cambridge 2003)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Orchard</surname>, <given-names>Andy, Pride</given-names></author> <title>and Prodigies. Studies in the Monsters of the Beowulf-Manuscript</title> (<other>Cambridge</other> <year>1995</year>)<raw>Orchard, Andy, Pride and Prodigies. Studies in the Monsters of the Beowulf-Manuscript (Cambridge 1995)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Osborn</surname>, <given-names>Marijane, „The</given-names></author> <author><surname>Great Feud</surname></author> <title>Scriptural History and Strife</title>“, in: <source>Beowulf. Basic Readings</source> hrsg. von <editor>Peter S</editor> <other>Baker (New York</other> <year>1995</year>)<raw>Osborn, Marijane, „The Great Feud: Scriptural History and Strife“, in: Beowulf. Basic Readings, hrsg. von Peter S. Baker (New York 1995)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Panzer</surname>, <given-names>Friedrich</given-names></author>, <title>Studien zur germanischen Sagengeschichte</title>. <other>I. Beowulf (München</other> <year>1910</year>)<raw>Panzer, Friedrich, Studien zur germanischen Sagengeschichte. I. Beowulf (München 1910)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Parker</surname>, <given-names>Mary A.</given-names></author> <title>Beowulf and Christianity</title> (<other>New York 1987)</other><raw>Parker, Mary A., Beowulf and Christianity (New York 1987)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Puhvel</surname>, <given-names>Martin, Beowulf</given-names></author> <title>and Celtic Tradition</title> (<other>Waterloo</other> <year>1979</year>)<raw>Puhvel, Martin, Beowulf and Celtic Tradition (Waterloo 1979)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Rauer</surname>, <given-names>Christine, Beowulf</given-names></author> <title>and the Dragon. Parallels and Analogues</title> (<other>Cambridge</other> <year>2000</year>)<raw>Rauer, Christine, Beowulf and the Dragon. Parallels and Analogues (Cambridge 2000)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Risden</surname>, <given-names>Edward L.</given-names></author> <title>Beasts of Time</title>. <other>Apocalyptic Beowulf (New York</other> <year>1994</year>)<raw>Risden, Edward L., Beasts of Time. Apocalyptic Beowulf (New York 1994)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Robinson</surname>, <given-names>Fred C.</given-names></author> “<title>Elements of the Marvellous in the Characterization of Beowulf: A Reconsideration of the Textual Evidence</title>”, in: <source>Beowulf. Basic Readings</source> hrsg. von <editor>Peter S</editor> <other>Baker (New York</other> <year>1995</year>), S. <fpage>79</fpage> - <lpage>96</lpage><raw>Robinson, Fred C., “Elements of the Marvellous in the Characterization of Beowulf: A Reconsideration of the Textual Evidence”, in: Beowulf. Basic Readings, hrsg. von Peter S. Baker (New York 1995), S. 79-96</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Robinson</surname>, <given-names>Fred C.</given-names></author> “<title>Teaching the Backgrounds. History, Religion, Culture</title>”, in: <source>Approaches to Teaching Beowulf</source> hrsg. von <editor>Jess B. Bessinger</editor> und <editor>Robert F</editor> <other>Yeager (New York</other> <year>1984</year>), S. <fpage>107</fpage> - <lpage>122</lpage><raw>Robinson, Fred C., “Teaching the Backgrounds. History, Religion, Culture”, in: Approaches to Teaching Beowulf, hrsg. von Jess B. Bessinger und Robert F. Yeager (New York 1984), S. 107-122</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Schubel</surname>, <given-names>F</given-names></author>., <title>Probleme der Beowulf Forschung</title> (<other>Darmstadt</other> <year>1979</year>)<raw>Schubel, F., Probleme der Beowulf Forschung (Darmstadt 1979)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Scowcroft</surname>, <given-names>Mark R.</given-names></author> “<title>The Irish Analogues to Beowulf”, Speculum</title>. <source>A Journal of Mediaeval Studies</source> <volume>74</volume> (<year>1999</year>), <fpage>22</fpage> - <lpage>64</lpage><raw>Scowcroft, Mark R., “The Irish Analogues to Beowulf”, Speculum. A Journal of Mediaeval Studies 74 (1999), 22-64</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stanley</surname>, <given-names>Eric G.</given-names></author> <title>In the Foreground: Beowulf</title> (<other>Cambridge</other> <year>1994</year>)<raw>Stanley, Eric G., In the Foreground: Beowulf (Cambridge 1994)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stanley</surname>, <given-names>Eric G.</given-names></author> “<title>Beowulf”</title> in: <source>Beowulf. Basic Readings</source> hrsg. von <editor>Peter S. Baker</editor> (<other>New York</other> <year>1995</year>), S. <fpage>3</fpage> - <lpage>34</lpage><raw>Stanley, Eric G., “Beowulf”, in: Beowulf. Basic Readings, hrsg. von Peter S. Baker (New York 1995), S. 3-34</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stitt</surname>, <given-names>Michael J.</given-names></author> <title>Beowulf and the Bear’s Son: Epic, Saga, and Fairytale in Northern Germanic Tradition</title>, (<other>New York 1992)</other><raw>Stitt, Michael J., Beowulf and the Bear’s Son: Epic, Saga, and Fairytale in Northern Germanic Tradition, (New York 1992)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Tolkien</surname>, <given-names>John R.R.</given-names></author> „<title>The Monsters and the Critics</title>“, in: <source>Interpretations of Beowulf. A Critical Anthology</source> hrsg. von <editor>Robert D. Fulk</editor> (<other>Bloomington</other> <year>1991</year>), S. <fpage>14</fpage> - <lpage>44</lpage><raw>Tolkien, John R.R., „The Monsters and the Critics“, in: Interpretations of Beowulf. A Critical Anthology, hrsg. von Robert D. Fulk (Bloomington 1991), S. 14-44</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Wild</surname>, <given-names>Friedrich</given-names></author>, <title>Drachen im Beowulf und andere Drachen</title> (<other>Graz</other> <year>1962</year>)<raw>Wild, Friedrich, Drachen im Beowulf und andere Drachen (Graz 1962)</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Williams</surname>, <given-names>David, Cain</given-names></author> <title>and Beowulf: A Study in Secular Allegory</title> (<other>Toronto</other> <year>1982</year>)<raw>Williams, David, Cain and Beowulf: A Study in Secular Allegory (Toronto 1982)</raw></sequence>