<sequence><author><surname>Kant</surname>, <given-names>Immanuel</given-names></author>: „<title>Kritik der Urteilskraft</title>“. Hg. <editor>Weischedel, Wilhelm. Suhrkamp</editor> <other>Frankfurt am Main</other> <year>2009</year>.<raw>Kant, Immanuel: „Kritik der Urteilskraft“. Hg. Weischedel, Wilhelm. Suhrkamp. Frankfurt am Main. 2009.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bloom</surname>, <given-names>Harold</given-names></author>: „<title>The Western Canon</title>“. <publisher>Riverhead Books</publisher> <other>New York</other> <year>1995</year><raw>Bloom, Harold: „The Western Canon“. Riverhead Books. New York. 1995</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lamping</surname>, <given-names>Dieter</given-names></author> und <author><surname>Zipfel</surname></author>, <other>Franz</other>: „<title>Was sollen Komparatisten lesen</title>.“ <publisher>Erich Schmidt Verlag</publisher> <other>Berlin</other>. <year>2005</year>.<raw>Lamping, Dieter und Zipfel, Franz: „Was sollen Komparatisten lesen.“ Erich Schmidt Verlag. Berlin. 2005.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Löffler</surname>, <given-names>Sigrid</given-names></author>: „<title>Die neue Weltliteratur und ihre großen Erzähler</title>“. <other>C.H</other>. <publisher>Beck</publisher>. <other>München. 2014</other><raw>Löffler, Sigrid: „Die neue Weltliteratur und ihre großen Erzähler“. C.H. Beck. München. 2014.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Rosendahl</surname> <given-names>Thomsen</given-names></author>, <title>Mads: „Mapping World Literature. International Canonization and Transnational Literatures</title>.” <other>Continuum. London</other> <year>2008</year>.<raw>Rosendahl Thomsen, Mads: „Mapping World Literature. International Canonization and Transnational Literatures.” Continuum. London 2008.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Szegedy-Masczák</surname>, <given-names>Mihály</given-names></author>: “<title>Literary Canons: National and International”. Akadémiai Kiad</title>ó. <other>Budapest</other>. <year>2001</year>.<raw>Szegedy-Masczák, Mihály: “Literary Canons: National and International”. Akadémiai Kiadó. Budapest. 2001.</raw></sequence><sequence><publisher>Artikel</publisher><raw>Artikel</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Albrecht</surname>, <given-names>Monika</given-names></author>: „<title>Doppelter Standard und postkoloniale Regelpoetik. Eine kritische Revision Postkolonialer Studien</title>. In: <source>Postkolonialismus und Kanon</source> Hg. <source>Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut</source> <other>Iulia</other> - <other>Karin</other>. <publisher>Aisthesis Verlag</publisher> <other>Bielefeld</other>. <year>2012</year>.<raw>Albrecht, Monika: „Doppelter Standard und postkoloniale Regelpoetik. Eine kritische Revision Postkolonialer Studien. In: Postkolonialismus und Kanon. Hg. Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut, Iulia - Karin. Aisthesis Verlag. Bielefeld. 2012.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Anz</surname>, <given-names>Thomas</given-names></author>: „<title>Einführung“</title> In: <editor>Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other>. <year>1998</year>.<raw>Anz, Thomas: „Einführung“. In: Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler. Stuttgart. 1998.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Balakian</surname>, <given-names>Anna</given-names></author>: „<title>Canon Harassment</title>“. In: <source>Canadian Review of Comparative</source> <other>Literature. März</other> - Juni <year>1993</year>.<raw>Balakian, Anna: „Canon Harassment“. In: Canadian Review of Comparative Literature. März - Juni 1993.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Brinker-Gabler</surname>, <given-names>Gisela</given-names></author>: „<title>Vom nationalen Kanon zur postnationalen Konstellation</title>. In: <editor>Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other>. <year>1998</year>.<raw>Brinker-Gabler, Gisela: „Vom nationalen Kanon zur postnationalen Konstellation. In: Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler. Stuttgart. 1998.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Cancik</surname>, <given-names>Hubert</given-names></author>: “<title>Kanon, Ritus, Ritual - Religionsgeschichtliche Anmerkungen zu einem literaturwissenschaftlichen Diskurs</title>.“ In: <source>Kanon und Theorie</source> <publisher>Universitätsverlag C. Winter</publisher> <other>Heidelberg</other>. <year>1997</year>.<raw>Cancik, Hubert: “Kanon, Ritus, Ritual - Religionsgeschichtliche Anmerkungen zu einem literaturwissenschaftlichen Diskurs.“ In: Kanon und Theorie. Universitätsverlag C. Winter. Heidelberg. 1997.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Dimi</surname>ć, <given-names>Milan V.</given-names></author> „<title>Why Study Canonization</title>“. In: <source>Canadian Review of Comparative Literature</source> <other>March-June</other>. <year>1993</year>.<raw>Dimić, Milan V.: „Why Study Canonization“. In: Canadian Review of Comparative Literature. March-June. 1993.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Fokkema</surname>, <given-names>Douwe</given-names></author>: “<title>Comparative Literature and the Problem of Canon Formation</title>”. In: <source>Canadian Review of Comparative Literature</source> <other>March</other>. <year>1996</year>.<raw>Fokkema, Douwe: “Comparative Literature and the Problem of Canon Formation”. In: Canadian Review of Comparative Literature. March. 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Göttsche</surname>, <given-names>Dirk</given-names></author>: “<title>Deutsche Literatur afrikanischer Diaspora und die Frage postkolonialer Kanonrevision</title>. In: <source>Postkolonialismus und Kanon</source> Hg. <source>Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut</source> <other>Iulia</other> - <other>Karin</other>. <publisher>Aisthesis Verlag</publisher> <other>Bielefeld</other>. <year>2012</year>.<raw>Göttsche, Dirk: “Deutsche Literatur afrikanischer Diaspora und die Frage postkolonialer Kanonrevision. In: Postkolonialismus und Kanon. Hg. Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut, Iulia - Karin. Aisthesis Verlag. Bielefeld. 2012.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Harris</surname>, <given-names>Wendell V.</given-names></author> „<title>Aligning Curricular Canons with Academic Programs</title>. In: <source>The Comparatist</source> Vol. <volume>24</volume>. <other>Mai</other>. <year>2000</year>.<raw>Harris, Wendell V.: „Aligning Curricular Canons with Academic Programs. In: The Comparatist. Vol. 24. Mai. 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lawall</surname>, <given-names>Sarah</given-names></author>: “<title>Canones, Contexts, and Perdagogoy: The Place of World Literature</title>. In: <source>The Comparatist</source> Vol. <volume>24</volume>. <other>Mai</other>. <year>2000</year>.<raw>Lawall, Sarah: “Canones, Contexts, and Perdagogoy: The Place of World Literature. In: The Comparatist. Vol. 24. Mai. 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Livingston</surname>, <given-names>Paisley</given-names></author>: „<title>Justifying the Canon</title>“. In: <title>The Search for a New Alphabet. Literary Studies in a Changing World</title>. <publisher>John Benjamin Publishing. Amsterdam</publisher> <year>1996</year>.<raw>Livingston, Paisley: „Justifying the Canon“. In: The Search for a New Alphabet. Literary Studies in a Changing World. John Benjamin Publishing. Amsterdam. 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lüsebrink</surname>, <given-names>Hans</given-names></author> <author><surname>- Jürgen</surname></author> „<title>Zentrum und Peripherie. Kulturhegemonie und Kanonwandel in (post-)kolonialen frankophonen Kulturen Afrikas und Amerikas</title>“. In: <editor>Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other>. <year>1998</year>.<raw>Lüsebrink, Hans - Jürgen: „Zentrum und Peripherie. Kulturhegemonie und Kanonwandel in (post-)kolonialen frankophonen Kulturen Afrikas und Amerikas“. In: Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler. Stuttgart. 1998.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Mecklenburg</surname>, <given-names>Norbert</given-names></author>: „‘<title>Kanon’ und ‘Weltliteratur’ auf interkulturellem und postkolonialem Prüfstand</title>. In: <source>Postkolonialismus und Kanon“</source> Hg. <source>Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut</source> <other>Iulia</other> - <other>Karin</other>. <publisher>Aisthesis Verlag</publisher> <other>Bielefeld</other>. <year>2012</year>.<raw>Mecklenburg, Norbert: „‘Kanon’ und ‘Weltliteratur’ auf interkulturellem und postkolonialem Prüfstand. In: Postkolonialismus und Kanon“. Hg. Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut, Iulia - Karin. Aisthesis Verlag. Bielefeld. 2012.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Miner</surname>, <given-names>Earl</given-names></author>: „<title>Canons and Comparatists</title>“. In: <source>The Search</source> <title>for a New Alphabet. Literary Studies in a Changing World</title>. <publisher>John Benjamin Publishing. Amsterdam</publisher> <year>1996</year>.<raw>Miner, Earl: „Canons and Comparatists“. In: The Search for a New Alphabet. Literary Studies in a Changing World. John Benjamin Publishing. Amsterdam. 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Schoene</surname>, <given-names>Berthold</given-names></author>: „<title>Weltliteratur und kosmopolitische Literatur</title>. In: <source>Handbuch Kanon und Wertung. Theorien, Instanzen Geschichte</source> Hg. <source>Rippl, Gabriele</source> und <editor>Winko, Simone. J. B. Metzler</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other>. <year>2013</year>.<raw>Schoene, Berthold: „Weltliteratur und kosmopolitische Literatur. In: Handbuch Kanon und Wertung. Theorien, Instanzen Geschichte. Hg. Rippl, Gabriele und Winko, Simone. J. B. Metzler. Stuttgart. 2013.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Smoot</surname>, <given-names>Jeanne J.</given-names></author> “<title>Multiculturalism, Censorship, and the Postmodern Assault on the Canon: Classical Answers to Contemporary Dilemmas</title>. In: <source>The Comparatist</source> Vol. <volume>24</volume>. <other>Mai 2000</other><raw>Smoot, Jeanne J.: “Multiculturalism, Censorship, and the Postmodern Assault on the Canon: Classical Answers to Contemporary Dilemmas. In: The Comparatist. Vol. 24. Mai 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Uerlings</surname>, <given-names>Herbert</given-names></author> <title>und Patrut, Iulia-Karin: „Postkolonialismus als Provokation für die Literaturwissenschaft</title>  <title>Eine Einleitung</title>“. In: <source>Postkolonialismus und Kanon</source> Hg. <source>Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut</source> <other>Iulia</other> - <other>Karin</other>. <publisher>Aisthesis Verlag</publisher> <other>Bielefeld</other>. <year>2012</year>.<raw>Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut, Iulia-Karin: „Postkolonialismus als Provokation für die Literaturwissenschaft . Eine Einleitung“. In: Postkolonialismus und Kanon. Hg. Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut, Iulia - Karin. Aisthesis Verlag. Bielefeld. 2012.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Uerlings</surname>, <given-names>Herbert</given-names></author>: „<title>Postkolonialismus und Kanon</title> ..“ In <source>Postkolonialismus und Kanon</source> Hg. <editor>Uerlings, Herbert</editor> und <author><surname>Patrut</surname></author>, <other>Iulia</other> <fpage>-</fpage> <other>Karin</other>. <publisher>Aisthesis Verlag</publisher> <other>Bielefeld</other>. <year>2012</year>.<raw>Uerlings, Herbert: „Postkolonialismus und Kanon.“ . In: Postkolonialismus und Kanon. Hg. Uerlings, Herbert und Patrut, Iulia - Karin. Aisthesis Verlag. Bielefeld. 2012.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Unt</surname>, <given-names>Marja</given-names></author>: “<title>The National Literary Canon in the Field of Tension Between Aesthetic and Ideological Principles. The Estonian Case with Indications to the Comparatives Perspectives</title>”. In: <source>Interlitteraria</source>. <year>2013</year>.<raw>Unt, Marja: “The National Literary Canon in the Field of Tension Between Aesthetic and Ideological Principles. The Estonian Case with Indications to the Comparatives Perspectives”. In: Interlitteraria. 2013.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Wägenbaur</surname>, <given-names>Thomas</given-names></author>: „‘<title>Gegen - Welt - Literatur‘ - Der Beitrag des Dekonstruktivismus zur gegenwärtigen Veränderung des komparatistischen Kanons</title>“. In: <source>Kanon und Theorie</source> <publisher>Universitätsverlag C. Winter</publisher> <other>Heidelberg</other>. <year>1997</year>.<raw>Wägenbaur, Thomas: „‘Gegen - Welt - Literatur‘ - Der Beitrag des Dekonstruktivismus zur gegenwärtigen Veränderung des komparatistischen Kanons“. In: Kanon und Theorie. Universitätsverlag C. Winter. Heidelberg. 1997.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Witt</surname>, <given-names>Mary Ann</given-names></author> <author><surname>Frese</surname></author>: „<title>Issues of the Canon: Introduction</title>”. In: <source>The Comparatist</source> Vol. <volume>24</volume>. <other>Mai 2000</other><raw>Witt, Mary Ann Frese: „Issues of the Canon: Introduction”. In: The Comparatist. Vol. 24. Mai 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Witt</surname>, <given-names>Mary Anne</given-names></author> <author><surname>Frese</surname></author>: „<title>Are the Canon Wars Over?: Rethinking Great Books</title>”. In: <source>The Comparatist</source> Vol. <volume>24</volume>. <other>Mai 2000</other><raw>Witt, Mary Anne Frese: „Are the Canon Wars Over?: Rethinking Great Books”. In: The Comparatist. Vol. 24. Mai 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Worthmann</surname>, <given-names>Friederike</given-names></author>: „<title>Literarische Kanones als Lektüremacht. Systematische Überlegungen zum Verhältnis von Kanon(isierung) und Wert(ung</title>)“. In: <editor>Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other>. <year>1998</year>.<raw>Worthmann, Friederike: „Literarische Kanones als Lektüremacht. Systematische Überlegungen zum Verhältnis von Kanon(isierung) und Wert(ung)“. In: Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler. Stuttgart. 1998.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Zymner</surname>, <given-names>Rüdiger</given-names></author>: „<title>Anspielung und Kanon</title> In: <editor>Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler</editor> <other>Stuttgart</other>. <year>1998</year>.<raw>Zymner, Rüdiger: „Anspielung und Kanon In: Kanon - Macht - Kultur. Hg. Heydebrand, Renate. J.B. Metzler. Stuttgart. 1998.</raw></sequence>