<sequence><author><surname>Brinton</surname>, <given-names>Laurel J</given-names></author> <year>1988</year>. <title>The Development of English aspectual systems. Aspectualizers and post-verbal particles</title>. <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>Brinton, Laurel J. 1988. The Development of English aspectual systems. Aspectualizers and post-verbal particles. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Bybee</surname>, <given-names>Joan L.</given-names></author> <author><surname>Dahl</surname>, <given-names>Östen</given-names></author>. <year>1989</year>. <title>The creation of tense and aspect systems in the languages of the world</title>. In: <source>Studies in Language</source> <volume>13-1</volume>. <fpage>51</fpage> - <lpage>103</lpage>.<raw>Bybee, Joan L.; Dahl, Östen. 1989. The creation of tense and aspect systems in the languages of the world. In: Studies in Language 13-1. 51–103.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Delbecque</surname>, <given-names>Nicole</given-names></author>. <year>2006</year>. <title>Linguistique cognitive. Comprendre comment fonctionne le langage</title>. <other>Bruxelles</other>: <publisher>DeBoeck</publisher>.<raw>Delbecque, Nicole. 2006. Linguistique cognitive. Comprendre comment fonctionne le langage. Bruxelles: DeBoeck.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Diewald</surname>, <given-names>Gabriele</given-names></author>. <year>1997</year>. <title>Grammatikalisierung. Eine Einführung in Sein und Werden grammatischer Formen</title>. <other>Berlin</other>: <publisher>De Gruyter</publisher><raw>Diewald, Gabriele. 1997. Grammatikalisierung. Eine Einführung in Sein und Werden grammatischer Formen. Berlin: De Gruyter.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Givón</surname>, <given-names>Talmy</given-names></author>. <year>1979</year>. <title>On Understanding Grammar</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>Academic Press</publisher><raw>Givón, Talmy. 1979. On Understanding Grammar. New York: Academic Press.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hopper</surname>, <given-names>Paul J.</given-names></author> <author><surname>Traugott</surname>, <given-names>Elizabeth Closs</given-names></author> <year>1993</year>. <title>Grammaticalization</title> <other>Cambridge</other>: <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>Hopper, Paul J.; Traugott, Elizabeth Closs. 1993. Grammaticalization. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Huchon</surname>, <given-names>Mireille</given-names></author>. <year>2002</year>. <title>Histoire de la langue française. Pairs: Le Livre de Poche</title> <author><surname>Klump</surname>, <given-names>Andre</given-names></author>. <year>2007</year>. <title>Trajectoires du changement linguistique. Zum Phänomen der Grammatikalisierung im Französischen</title>. <other>Stuttgart</other>: <publisher>Ibidem-Verlag</publisher>.<raw>Huchon, Mireille. 2002. Histoire de la langue française. Pairs: Le Livre de Poche Klump, Andre. 2007. Trajectoires du changement linguistique. Zum Phänomen der Grammatikalisierung im Französischen. Stuttgart: Ibidem-Verlag.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lehmann</surname>, <given-names>Christian</given-names></author>. <year>2013a</year>. <title>Linguistics. Sprachen. Indo-european languages. Romanische Sprachgeschichte</title>. Ch. <volume>14.1</volume>. Hg. v <editor>Universität Erfurt</editor> <other>Erfurt. Online</other> verfügbar unter <url>https://www.christianlehmann.eu/ling/sprachen/indogermania/RomGesch/</url> <other>zuletzt aktualisiert am 11.09.13, zuletzt geprüft am 09.04.20</other><raw>Lehmann, Christian. 2013a. Linguistics. Sprachen. Indo-european languages. Romanische Sprachgeschichte. Ch. 14.1. Hg. v. Universität Erfurt. Erfurt. Online verfügbar unter https://www.christianlehmann.eu/ling/sprachen/indogermania/RomGesch/, zuletzt aktualisiert am 11.09.13, zuletzt geprüft am 09.04.20.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lehmann</surname>, <given-names>Christian</given-names></author>. <year>2013b</year>: <title>Linguistics. Sprachwandel</title>. Ch. <volume>6.2</volume>. Hg. v <editor>Universität Erfurt</editor> <other>Erfurt. Online</other> verfügbar unter <url>https://www.christianlehmann.eu/ling/wandel/</url> <other>zuletzt aktualisiert am 11.09.13, zuletzt geprüft am 09.04.20</other><raw>Lehmann, Christian. 2013b: Linguistics. Sprachwandel. Ch. 6.2. Hg. v. Universität Erfurt. Erfurt. Online verfügbar unter https://www.christianlehmann.eu/ling/wandel/, zuletzt aktualisiert am 11.09.13, zuletzt geprüft am 09.04.20.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lehmann</surname>, <given-names>Christian</given-names></author>. <year>1995</year>. <title>Thoughts on grammaticalization</title>. <source>Rev. and expanded version, 1. publ</source> ed. <other>München i.e. Unterschleissheim</other> <publisher>LINCOM Europa</publisher><raw>Lehmann, Christian. 1995. Thoughts on grammaticalization. Rev. and expanded version, 1. publ. ed. München i.e. Unterschleissheim: LINCOM Europa.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Meillet</surname>, <given-names>Antoine</given-names></author>. <year>1912 1958</year> <title>L'évolution des formes grammaticales. In Antoine Meillet, Linguistique historique et linguistique générale. 130-148</title> (<source>Erstfassung in Rivista di scienzia</source> <volume>12</volume> no. <issue>26, 6)</issue> van <author><surname>Goethem</surname>, <given-names>Kristel</given-names></author>. <year>2008</year>. <title>Oud-leerling versus ancien élève: A Comparative Study of Adjectives Grammaticalizing into Prefixes in Dutch and French</title>. <source>Morphology</source> <volume>18</volume> (<issue>1</issue>). <fpage>27</fpage> - <lpage>49</lpage>.<raw>Meillet, Antoine. 1912 1958. L'évolution des formes grammaticales. In Antoine Meillet, Linguistique historique et linguistique générale. 130-148 (Erstfassung in Rivista di scienzia 12 no. 26, 6). van Goethem, Kristel. 2008. Oud-leerling versus ancien élève: A Comparative Study of Adjectives Grammaticalizing into Prefixes in Dutch and French. Morphology 18 (1). 27–49.</raw></sequence>