<sequence><author><surname>Bal</surname>, <given-names>Mieke </given-names></author> <year>1981</year>. “<title>Notes on narrative embedding</title>.” <source>Poetics Today</source> <volume>2</volume>: <fpage>41</fpage> - <lpage>59</lpage><raw>Bal, Mieke . 1981. “Notes on narrative embedding.” Poetics Today 2: 41-59</raw></sequence><sequence><title>The Narrating and the Focalizing: A Theorie of the Agents in Narrative</title>.” <source>Style</source> <volume>17.2</volume>: <fpage>234</fpage> - <lpage>269</lpage> <author><surname>Banville</surname></author>, John. <year>1990</year>. <source>The Book of Evidence. Minerva paperback edition</source> <other>London</other>: <publisher>Secker & Warburg</publisher><raw>The Narrating and the Focalizing: A Theorie of the Agents in Narrative.” Style 17.2: 234-269 Banville, John. 1990. The Book of Evidence. Minerva paperback edition. London: Secker & Warburg.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Ghosts</surname></author>. <other>London</other>: <publisher>Secker</publisher> <other>& Warburg/New York</other> <publisher>Knopf</publisher>.<raw>Ghosts. London: Secker & Warburg/New York: Knopf.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Berendsen</surname>, <given-names>Mariet</given-names></author>. <year>1984</year>. “<title>The Teller and the Observer: Narration and Focalization in Narrative</title> <source>Texts.” Style</source> <volume>18.2</volume>: <fpage>140</fpage> - <lpage>158</lpage><raw>Berendsen, Mariet. 1984. “The Teller and the Observer: Narration and Focalization in Narrative Texts.” Style 18.2: 140-158</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Brown</surname>, <given-names>Terence</given-names></author>. <year>1991</year>. “<title>Redeeming the Time: The Novels of John McGahern and John Banville</title>.” In: <editor>Acheson, James</editor> Hg. <source>The British and Irish</source> <title>Novel since 1960</title>. <other>New York</other> <publisher>St. Martin’s</publisher> <fpage>159</fpage> - <lpage>173</lpage><raw>Brown, Terence. 1991. “Redeeming the Time: The Novels of John McGahern and John Banville.” In: Acheson, James, Hg. The British and Irish Novel since 1960. New York: St. Martin’s. 159-173</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Füger</surname>, <given-names>Wilhelm</given-names></author>. <year>1993</year>. “<title>Stimmbrüche: Varianten und Spielräume narrativer Fokalisation</title>.” In: <editor>Foltinek, Herbert</editor> Hg. <source>Tales and</source> “ <title>their telling difference</title> ”  <source>Festschrift für</source> <editor>Franz K. Stanzel</editor> <other>Heidelberg</other>: <publisher>Winter</publisher>. <fpage>43</fpage> - <lpage>59</lpage><raw>Füger, Wilhelm. 1993. “Stimmbrüche: Varianten und Spielräume narrativer Fokalisation.” In: Foltinek, Herbert, Hg. Tales and “ their telling difference ” : Festschrift für Franz K. Stanzel. Heidelberg: Winter. 43-59</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Genette</surname>, <given-names>Gérard</given-names></author>. <year>1980</year>. <title>Narrative Discourse</title>. trans. <editor>Jane E. Lewin</editor> <other>Oxford</other>: <publisher>Blackwell</publisher>.<raw>Genette, Gérard. 1980. Narrative Discourse. trans. Jane E. Lewin. Oxford: Blackwell.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Hof</surname>, <given-names>Renate</given-names></author>. <year>1984</year>. <title>Das Spiel des unreliable Narrator: Aspekte unglaubwürdigen Erzählens im Werk von Vladi- mir Nabokov</title>. <other>München</other>: <publisher>Fink</publisher>.<raw>Hof, Renate. 1984. Das Spiel des unreliable Narrator: Aspekte unglaubwürdigen Erzählens im Werk von Vladi- mir Nabokov. München: Fink.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Imhof</surname>, <given-names>Rüdiger</given-names></author>. <year>1989</year>. <title>John Banville: A Critical Introduction</title>. <other>Dublin</other>: <publisher>Wolfhound</publisher>.<raw>Imhof, Rüdiger. 1989. John Banville: A Critical Introduction. Dublin: Wolfhound.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Jahn</surname>, <given-names>Manfred</given-names></author>. <year>1995</year>. “<title>Narratologie: Methoden und Modelle der Erzähltheorie</title>.” In: <editor>Nünning, Ansgar</editor> Hg. Litera- <title>turwissenschaftliche Theorien, Modelle, Methoden: Eine Einführung</title>. <other>Trier</other>: <publisher>Wissenschaftlicher Verlag Trier</publisher> <fpage>29</fpage> - <lpage>50</lpage><raw>Jahn, Manfred. 1995. “Narratologie: Methoden und Modelle der Erzähltheorie.” In: Nünning, Ansgar. Hg. Litera- turwissenschaftliche Theorien, Modelle, Methoden: Eine Einführung. Trier: Wissenschaftlicher Verlag Trier. 29-50</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Jahn</surname>, <given-names>Manfred</given-names></author>; <author><surname>Nünning</surname>, <given-names>Ansgar</given-names></author>. <year>1990</year>. “<title>Kurzgeschichten von Ian McEwan in einem Englisch-Leistungskurs: Darstellung grotesker Welten aus der Perspektive des ,verrückten Monologisten</title>’.” <source>Literatur in Wissenschaft und Unterricht</source> <volume>23</volume>. <issue>1</issue>. S. <fpage>36</fpage> - <lpage>50</lpage><raw>Jahn, Manfred; Nünning, Ansgar. 1990. “Kurzgeschichten von Ian McEwan in einem Englisch-Leistungskurs: Darstellung grotesker Welten aus der Perspektive des ,verrückten Monologisten’.” Literatur in Wissenschaft und Unterricht 23. 1. S. 36-50</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>A</surname></author> <title>Survey of Narratological Methods</title>.” <source>Literatur in Wissenschaft und Unterricht</source> <volume>27.4</volume>: <fpage>283</fpage> - <lpage>303</lpage><raw>A Survey of Narratological Methods.” Literatur in Wissenschaft und Unterricht 27.4: 283-303</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Lanser</surname>, <given-names>Susan Sniader</given-names></author> <year>1981</year>. <title>The Narrative Act: Point of View in Prose Fiction</title>. <other>Princeton</other>: <publisher>Princeton UP</publisher><raw>Lanser, Susan Sniader. 1981. The Narrative Act: Point of View in Prose Fiction. Princeton: Princeton UP.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Magill</surname>, <given-names>Frank N</given-names></author> Hg. <year>1991</year>. <title>Critical Survey Of Long Fiction. (English Language Series</title>.) <source>Revised Edition</source> Bd. <volume>1</volume>. <other>Pasadena (CAL)</other> <publisher>Salem Press</publisher><raw>Magill, Frank N. Hg. 1991. Critical Survey Of Long Fiction. (English Language Series.) Revised Edition. Bd. 1. Pasadena (CAL): Salem Press</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>McMinn</surname>, <given-names>Joseph</given-names></author>. <year>1991</year>. <given-names>John</given-names> <author><surname>Banville</surname></author>: <title>A Critical Study. (Gill’s Studies in Irish Literature</title>). <other>Dublin</other>: <publisher>Gill & Macmil- lan</publisher><raw>McMinn, Joseph. 1991. John Banville: A Critical Study. (Gill’s Studies in Irish Literature). Dublin: Gill & Macmil- lan.</raw></sequence><sequence><title>Naming the World: Language and Experience in John Banville’s Fiction</title>.” <source>Irish University Review</source> <volume>23</volume> (<issue>Autumn/Winter</issue> <year>1993</year>): <fpage>183</fpage> - <lpage>196</lpage><raw>Naming the World: Language and Experience in John Banville’s Fiction.” Irish University Review 23  (Autumn/Winter 1993): 183-196</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Nünning</surname>, <given-names>Ansgar</given-names></author>. <year>1990</year>. “<title>Point of view oder focalization ? Über einige Grundlagen und Kategorien konkurrierender Modelle der erzählerischen Vermittlung</title>.” <source>Literatur in Wissenschaft und Unterricht</source> <volume>23.3</volume>: <fpage>249</fpage> - <lpage>268</lpage><raw>Nünning, Ansgar. 1990. “Point of view oder focalization ? Über einige Grundlagen und Kategorien konkurrierender Modelle der erzählerischen Vermittlung.” Literatur in Wissenschaft und Unterricht 23.3: 249-268</raw></sequence><sequence><title>a. Uni-Training englische Literaturwissenschaft</title>. <other>Stuttgart u.a.</other> <publisher>Klett-Verlag für Wissenschaft und Bil-</publisher> <other>dung</other>.<raw>a. Uni-Training englische Literaturwissenschaft. Stuttgart u.a.: Klett-Verlag für Wissenschaft und Bil- dung.</raw></sequence><sequence>b. “Zwischen <title>der realistischen Erzähltradition und der experimentellen Poetik des Postmodernismus: Er- scheinungsformen und Entwicklungstendenzen des englischen Romans seit dem Zweiten Weltkrieg aus gat- tungstheoretischer Perspektive</title>.” In: <editor>Nünning, Ansgar</editor> Hg. <title>Eine andere Geschichte der englischen Litera- tur: Epochen, Gattungen und Teilgebiete imüberblick</title>. <other>Trier</other>: <publisher>Wissenschaftlicher Verlag Trier</publisher> <fpage>213</fpage> - <lpage>240</lpage><raw>b. “Zwischen der realistischen Erzähltradition und der experimentellen Poetik des Postmodernismus: Er- scheinungsformen und Entwicklungstendenzen des englischen Romans seit dem Zweiten Weltkrieg aus gat- tungstheoretischer Perspektive.” In: Nünning, Ansgar. Hg. Eine andere Geschichte der englischen Litera- tur: Epochen, Gattungen und Teilgebiete imüberblick. Trier: Wissenschaftlicher Verlag Trier. 213-240</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Oxford Advanced</surname> <title>Learner ’ s Dictionary Of Current</title> <surname>English</surname> <given-names>(A</given-names></author> <author><surname>S Hornby)</surname></author> <year>1990</year>. <volume>4th</volume> ed. <issue>3rd</issue> impr. <other>Oxford</other> <publisher>: Oxford UP</publisher><raw>Oxford Advanced Learner ’ s Dictionary Of Current English (A S Hornby). 1990. 4th ed. 3rd impr. Oxford : Oxford UP.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Prince</surname>, <given-names>Gerald</given-names></author>. <year>1987</year>. <title>A Dictionary of Narratology</title>. <other>Lincoln & London</other> <publisher>University of Nebraska press</publisher><raw>Prince, Gerald. 1987. A Dictionary of Narratology. Lincoln & London: University of Nebraska press.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Q</surname></author>. and <title>A. with John Banville.” (Rüdiger Imhof interviewt John Banville). Irish Literary Supplement</title>. <other>Spring</other> <year>1987</year>.<raw>Q. and A. with John Banville.” (Rüdiger Imhof interviewt John Banville). Irish Literary Supplement. Spring 1987.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Stanzel</surname>, <given-names>Franz K</given-names></author> <year>1991</year>. <title>Theorie des Erzählens</title>. <issue>5</issue>. Aufl. <other>Göttingen</other>: <publisher>Vandenhoeck und Ruprecht</publisher><raw>Stanzel, Franz K. 1991. Theorie des Erzählens. 5. Aufl. Göttingen: Vandenhoeck und Ruprecht.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>Williams</surname>, <given-names>Linda R</given-names></author> Hg. <year>1992</year>. <title>The Twentieth Century: A Guide To Literature From 1900 To The Present Day. (Bloomsbury Guides to English Literature</title>). <other>London</other>: <publisher>Bloomsbury</publisher>.<raw>Williams, Linda R. Hg. 1992. The Twentieth Century: A Guide To Literature From 1900 To The Present Day.  (Bloomsbury Guides to English Literature). London: Bloomsbury.</raw></sequence>