<sequence><author><surname>AKOM</surname>, <given-names>A. A.</given-names></author> <title>Reexaming Resistance as Oppositional Behavior: The Nation of Islam and the Creation of a black Achievement Ideology</title>, in: <source>Sociology of Education</source> Vol. <volume>76</volume>, No. <issue>4</issue>, <year>2003</year>.<raw>AKOM, A. A.: Reexaming Resistance as Oppositional Behavior: The Nation of Islam and the Creation of a black Achievement Ideology, in: Sociology of Education, Vol. 76, No. 4, 2003.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>AL-TABARI</surname>, <given-names>Abu</given-names></author> <title>Ja'far Muhammad b. Jarir: The Commentary on the Qur'an</title>, <other>Oxford</other> <year>1989</year>.<raw>AL-TABARI, Abu Ja'far Muhammad b. Jarir: The Commentary on the Qur'an, Oxford 1989.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>ANSARI</surname>, <given-names>Zafar Ishaq</given-names></author> <title>Aspects of Black Muslim Theology</title>, in: <source>Studia Islamica</source> No. <volume>53</volume>, <year>1981</year>.<raw>ANSARI, Zafar Ishaq: Aspects of Black Muslim Theology, in: Studia Islamica, No. 53, 1981.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>BARRETT</surname>, <given-names>Paul M.</given-names></author> <title>American Islam, The Struggle For The Soul of a Religion</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>2007</year>.<raw>BARRETT, Paul M.: American Islam, The Struggle For The Soul of a Religion, New York 2007.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>CHAKRABARTY</surname>, <given-names>Dipesh</given-names></author>: <title>Subaltern Studies in Retrospect and Reminiscence</title>, <other>Chicago</other> <year>2005</year>.<raw>CHAKRABARTY, Dipesh: Subaltern Studies in Retrospect and Reminiscence, Chicago 2005.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>CHATERJEE</surname>, <given-names>Parta</given-names></author>: <title>Empire and Nation, Selected Essays</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>2010</year>.<raw>CHATERJEE, Parta: Empire and Nation, Selected Essays, New York 2010.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>CRAWFORD</surname>, <given-names>Malachi D.</given-names></author> <author><surname>Black</surname></author> <title>Muslims and the Law, Civil Liberties from Elijah Muhammad to Muhammad Ali</title>, <other>London</other> <year>2015</year>.<raw>CRAWFORD, Malachi D.: Black Muslims and the Law, Civil Liberties from Elijah Muhammad to Muhammad Ali, London 2015.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>CURTIS</surname>, <given-names>Edward E.</given-names></author> <title>African-American Islamization Reconsidered: Black History Narratives and Muslim Identity</title>, in: <source>Journal of the American Academy of Religion</source> Vol. <volume>73</volume>, No. <issue>3</issue>, <year>2005</year>.<raw>CURTIS, Edward E.: African-American Islamization Reconsidered: Black History Narratives and Muslim Identity, in: Journal of the American Academy of Religion, Vol. 73, No. 3, 2005.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>FRANKLIN</surname>, <given-names>V. P.</given-names></author> <author><surname>Black</surname></author> Self-Determination, Westport <year>1984</year>.<raw>FRANKLIN, V. P.: Black Self-Determination, Westport 1984.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GARDELL</surname>, <given-names>Mattias</given-names></author>: <title>Gods of the Blood, The Pagan Revival and White Seperatism</title>, <other>London</other> <year>2003</year>.<raw>GARDELL, Mattias: Gods of the Blood, The Pagan Revival and White Seperatism, London 2003.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GARDELL</surname>, <given-names>Mattias</given-names></author>: <title>In the Name of Elijah Muhammad, Louis Farrakhan and the Nation of Islam</title>, <other>Durham</other> <year>1996</year>.<raw>GARDELL, Mattias: In the Name of Elijah Muhammad, Louis Farrakhan and the Nation of Islam, Durham 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GARDELL</surname>, <given-names>Mattias</given-names></author>: <title>Countdown to Armageddon, Minister Farrakhan and the Nation of Islam in the Latter Days</title>, <other>Virginia</other> <year>1996</year>.<raw>GARDELL, Mattias: Countdown to Armageddon, Minister Farrakhan and the Nation of Islam in the Latter Days, Virginia 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GIBSON</surname>, <given-names>Dawn-Marie</given-names></author>: <title>A History of the Nation of Islam, Race, Islam, and the Quest for Freedom</title>, <other>Kalifornien</other> <year>2012</year>.<raw>GIBSON, Dawn-Marie: A History of the Nation of Islam, Race, Islam, and the Quest for Freedom, Kalifornien 2012.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>GREEN</surname>, <given-names>Markus E.</given-names></author> <title>Gramsci's Concept of Subaltern Social Groups</title>, <other>Toronto</other> <year>2006</year>.<raw>GREEN, Markus E.: Gramsci's Concept of Subaltern Social Groups, Toronto 2006.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>HOWELL</surname>, <given-names>Sally</given-names></author>: <title>Old Islam in Detroit, Rediscovering the Muslim American Past</title>, <other>Oxford</other> <year>2014</year>.<raw>HOWELL, Sally: Old Islam in Detroit, Rediscovering the Muslim American Past, Oxford 2014.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>HUNTER</surname>, <given-names>Margaret</given-names></author>: <title>The Persistent Problem of Colorism</title>, in: <source>Social Compass</source> Vol. <volume>1</volume>, No. <issue>1</issue>, <year>2007</year>.<raw>HUNTER, Margaret: The Persistent Problem of Colorism, in: Social Compass, Vol. 1, No. 1, 2007.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>JACKSON</surname>, <given-names>Sherman A.</given-names></author> <title>Islam and the Blackamerican, looking toward the Third Resurrection</title>, <other>Oxford</other> <year>2005</year>.<raw>JACKSON, Sherman A.: Islam and the Blackamerican, looking toward the Third Resurrection, Oxford 2005.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>KELLETLER</surname>, <given-names>Frank</given-names></author>: <title>Con/Tradition, Louis Farrakhan's Nation of Islam, the Million Man March, and American Civil Religion</title>, <other>Heidelberg</other> <year>2000</year>.<raw>KELLETLER, Frank: Con/Tradition, Louis Farrakhan's Nation of Islam, the Million Man March, and American Civil Religion, Heidelberg 2000.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>KHAN</surname>, <given-names>Katy</given-names></author>: <title>The influence of the Nation of Islam on African American singers</title>, In: <source>Journal of Music Research in Africa</source> Vol. <volume>8</volume>, <year>2011</year>.<raw>KHAN, Katy: The influence of the Nation of Islam on African American singers, In: Journal of Music Research in Africa, Vol. 8, 2011.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>KRÄMER</surname>, <given-names>Gudrun</given-names></author>: <title>Geschichte des Islam</title>, <other>München</other> <year>2005</year>.<raw>KRÄMER, Gudrun: Geschichte des Islam, München 2005.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>LEE</surname>, <given-names>Martha F.</given-names></author> <title>The Nation of Islam, An American Millenarian Movement</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>1996</year>.<raw>LEE, Martha F.: The Nation of Islam, An American Millenarian Movement, New York 1996.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>LINCOLN</surname>, <given-names>Eric C.</given-names></author> <title>The Negro Pilgrimage in America, The Coming of Age of the Blackamericans</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>1969</year>.<raw>LINCOLN, Eric C.: The Negro Pilgrimage in America, The Coming of Age of the Blackamericans, New York 1969.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>LOMAX</surname>, <given-names>Luis E.</given-names></author> <title>When the Word is Given, A Report on Elijah Muhammad, Malcolm X and the Black Muslim World</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>1963</year>.<raw>LOMAX, Luis E.: When the Word is Given, A Report on Elijah Muhammad, Malcolm X and the Black Muslim World, New York 1963.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>MCCUTCHEON</surname>, <given-names>Priscilla</given-names></author>: <title>Food, Faith, and the everyday struggle for black urban community</title>, <other>London</other> <year>2014</year>.<raw>MCCUTCHEON, Priscilla: Food, Faith, and the everyday struggle for black urban community, London 2014.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>MEIER</surname>, <given-names>August</given-names></author>: <title>From Plantation to Ghetto, An Interpretive History of the American Negroes</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>1966</year>.<raw>MEIER, August: From Plantation to Ghetto, An Interpretive History of the American Negroes, New York 1966.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>MERKENS</surname>, <given-names>Andreas</given-names></author>: <title>Die Regierten von den Regierenden intellektuell unabhängig machen, Gegenhegemonie, politische Bildung und Pädagogik bei Antonio Gramsci</title>, <other>Hamburg</other> <year>2004</year>.<raw>MERKENS, Andreas: Die Regierten von den Regierenden intellektuell unabhängig machen, Gegenhegemonie, politische Bildung und Pädagogik bei Antonio Gramsci, Hamburg 2004.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>PARET</surname>, <given-names>Rudi</given-names></author>: <title>Der Koran</title>, <other>Stuttgart</other> <year>2010</year>.<raw>PARET, Rudi: Der Koran, Stuttgart 2010.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>PINKNEY</surname>, <given-names>Alphonso</given-names></author>: <title>Black Americans</title>, <other>New York</other> <year>1987</year>.<raw>PINKNEY, Alphonso: Black Americans, New York 1987.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>SANDOVAL-STRAUSZ</surname>, <given-names>A.K</given-names></author>.: <author><surname>Travelers, Strangers</surname> and <given-names>Jim</given-names></author> <author><surname>Crow</surname></author>: <title>Law, Public Accommodations, and Civil Rights in America</title>, <other>Illinois</other> <year>2005</year>.<raw>SANDOVAL-STRAUSZ, A.K.: Travelers, Strangers, and Jim Crow: Law, Public Accommodations, and Civil Rights in America, Illinois 2005.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>SIMON</surname>, <given-names>Katrin</given-names></author>: <title>Die Erben des Malcolm X, Afroamerikanische Muslime zwischen Widerstand und Anpassung</title>, <other>Bielefeld</other> <year>2015</year>.<raw>SIMON, Katrin: Die Erben des Malcolm X, Afroamerikanische Muslime zwischen Widerstand und Anpassung, Bielefeld 2015.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>STEYERL</surname>, <given-names>Hito</given-names></author>: <title>Spricht die Subalterne deutsch? Migration und postkoloniale Kritik</title>, <other>Münster</other> <year>2003</year>.<raw>STEYERL, Hito: Spricht die Subalterne deutsch? Migration und postkoloniale Kritik, Münster 2003.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>WATSON</surname>, <given-names>Llewellyn G.</given-names></author> <title>Social Structure and Social Movements: The Black Muslims in the U.S.A. and the Rastafarians in Jamaica</title>, in: <source>The British Journal of Sociology</source> Vol. <volume>24</volume>, No. <issue>2</issue>, <year>1973</year>.<raw>WATSON, Llewellyn G.: Social Structure and Social Movements: The Black Muslims in the U.S.A. and the Rastafarians in Jamaica, in: The British Journal of Sociology, Vol. 24, No. 2, 1973.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>WEST</surname>, <given-names>Cornel</given-names></author>: <title>Race Matters</title>, <other>Boston</other> <year>1993</year>.<raw>WEST, Cornel: Race Matters, Boston 1993.</raw></sequence><sequence><author><surname>WHITE</surname>, <given-names>Vibert L.</given-names></author> <title>Inside the Nation of Islam, A historical and personal Testimony by a Black Muslim</title>, <other>Florida</other> <year>2001</year>.<raw>WHITE, Vibert L.: Inside the Nation of Islam, A historical and personal Testimony by a Black Muslim, Florida 2001.</raw></sequence>